[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Hello everybody and welcome to episode
263 of the Ask Abijit show. I hope
everybody is doing fantastic.
Everybody's doing great. I'm doing
fantastic. So let's see who all is there
on the live chat. Who all do we have
with us? I can see Vidimar anonymous
scientist. Herse Praneal from Kolkata.
Mystic SK Kuml Singh from Melbourne. Abi
Chandel 005. H global citizen devourer
of worlds. Shri Watson Duv Durya
Samarati Djamat Geopolitical Dub from
Indor Harsh
Yeti Yeti Anul
Kumar Kaneshka Mr. 88ers Antarami Arby
Oscar Madison from Texas Rahul Dunak Rat
Hane Rishikesh Das Gupta Vin Manisha
Matei Anul Rishikesh Chri Chhatan Aradya
Shubham Dub Animesh Paul Sam Malik sayad
sun-kissed
anonymous bindu
Krishna Nayak Vhan Patil Gautami Bamshi
Kalem
Mlavvin, Vikash, PJ, Avin, Nuro, Kumar,
Kanesh,
Sica from Dhaka, Random, Skull, Alvin,
Rodriguez, Kishor, Heanchu, Meta,
Gorish, KB, Hanul, Raj, Sager, Tu, Diam,
Jawan, Sedhart, Aush, Yadav and so many
other people. So, thank you so much all
of you for being on the live chat and
let us take some questions. Let's take
some questions. I can see there's a lot
of questions already. So let's going
with the let's get going with the
questions. What do we have? Kumar Kanesh
says, "What was the reason for the Royal
Indian Navy Mutiny and how big was it?"
The Royal Indian Navy Mutiny happened
because it it was at the end of the
Second World War. The Second World War
has had ended and all the Indian sailors
etc who had fought for the British all
across the world, Europe and so on so
forth. They were brought back to Bombay.
It was then called Bombay, not Mumbai.
It was called Bombay that back then.
They were all put in this row in the
barracks and they were very poorly
mistreated. They were not given proper
salaries. They were not allowed to be
discharged. They were just made to sit
there and and they were treated in a in
a very harsh way. There was a lot of
racism against them from their senior
officers. So eventually they got fed up
with it with it and they took control of
the entire Indian Navy, Royal Indian
Navy. It was big.
You had ships the every single ship
apart from two or three two we obvious
have some traitors right but apart from
two or three ships every every other
ship mutinate. So you had ships in the
Gulf of Mala you had ships off the co of
the coast of Adan of the coast of Yemen
you had ships in the Persian Gulf then
you had ships on the west coast of India
east coast of India near Sri Lanka near
Digaria all of these mutinated it was
enormous
enormous but the great Mr. Gandhi came
in the way and he ended the mutiny. Very
superb man Mr. Gandhi
Kumar Kaneska says how did the west
infuse civic sense in their public to
follow rules as India's birth rate is
going down? Is this a good thing to
reduce burden on resources? Well, there
are two different questions completely
separate. How did the west infuse civic
sense in the republic? By applying the
rule of law by imposing harsh
punishments.
That's how they did it. So you don't
necessarily need to impose harsh
punishments. I would say all you need to
do is to ensure that if you break the
rules, you will be punished even if the
punishment is mild. But who wants to be
punished over and over again? So they'll
change their habits, right? And their
attitude and behavior. So the west in
they they imposed the rule of law. They
ensured that anybody who broke the civic
sense and what what not would be
punished. The punishment was guaranteed.
Right. So that's how they made it
happen. Uh now India's birth rate, it's
it's a terrible thing. India's birth
rate is going down. We need our
population to come down eventually to
about 300 or so million like it always
was. But that should happen over a
couple of centuries, not in 2030 years.
Otherwise, everybody will be 60 plus
years old. The average median age of the
population will rise and there will be
very few young people left. That's a
disaster. So it's not good.
Mr. Ays says, "What was the Taiping
rebellion?" Well, you are taking us back
in history now. It is a it is the it was
a civil war that happened in China in
the 1850s all the way to the 1860s
and the the I forget the names of the
individuals the Chinese names I can't
remember but the the person who led the
rebellion was a convert to Christianity.
He said that he was the son or brother
or something of Jesus Christ. So
apparently Mr. Christ has as a brother
and this Chinese gentleman was that and
this Chinese guy who led the rebellion
wanted to completely completely change
the nature of Chinese society make China
a Christian um nation and so on and this
and and he gained a lot of followers
apparently and this went on for about 10
15 years this rebellion and I don't know
what the numbers are the the actual
death toll is but it's anywhere between
20 million to 100 million
And eventually the guy was found and
executed. His son became the successor.
He was also executed. At least one of
them was executed and so on. So it was a
civil war which devastated China. And it
was a it was a Christian insurrection
against Chinese civilization.
The typing rebellion.
Yati. Yati.
Yati. Well, thank you so much sir Mr.
Yati. Thank you.
Hersa says, "Sar, what's a think tank?
Explain deeply. A think tank is a
collection of individuals who share some
kind of expertise in a certain domain
and they come together and they produce
original research and original ideas
uh about this domain
and they and they write reports and
things and they they prescribe
uh courses of action that need to be
taken in order to make the domain a
better place that sort of thing. So one
of the simplest things is a geopolitical
think tank. This is of geopolitical
think tanks in India, right? So it's a
group of people who come together and
who who write up reports and they they
sometimes they're commissioned by
somebody. Maybe the government
commissions them or maybe some private
company commissions them and so on. So
that's a think tank. And for example,
let's say you're a big company. Okay,
you let's say you're a multinational
national company. And if you're a
multinational company, if you have
assets and holdings across the various
parts of the world, you are exposed to
geopolitical risk in various shapes and
forms. So you want to be able to know
what's coming, what could be coming and
how to deal with it. What's the best
course of action? So you hire experts,
you commission them, you pay them
whatever money and you tell them to
create these reports. Forecasting. Have
you watched the geost strategy with the
Vijay Chava? That's forecasting. You
watched Indian interest. It's
forecasting. I give scenarios. Scenario
A, scenario B, scenario C. This could
happen in this much time with this much
probability of happening. and my
scenarios are typically very spot-on,
aren't they? And so on. So that's I'm
like a one-man think tank, but typically
you have 15 20 people doing what I'm
what I do. So that's a think tank. So
you typically commission, you're
typically paid to do these things either
by the government or by a private
company, multinational corporation and
so on. And you do the research for them
and you give them recommendations,
deeply researched recommendations. You
write white papers and so on so forth.
So that's a think tank. So I'm a one-man
think tank essentially.
Uh um Aintia Anand says, "Do you know
about business plot Wall Street push
push push to overthrow FDR?" I'm not
aware of this. I'm sure it must have
happened, but I haven't read about this.
So, so
uh geopolitical Dubai. Well, first of
all, happy birthday, sir. It's your
birthday, so happy birthday. Uh I wish
you lots and lots and lots of very
happy, very robust returns of the day.
Thank you so much sir. Thank you. All
the best. Keep going.
Shankar Kulkarni says Timour seems to be
a better general compared to Alexander.
Started from Usbakistan, conquered
Persia, won battles in winter in Russia.
Sacked Deli, imprisoned Sultan Bayad.
Methods were brutal but superior.
Well,
I I haven't done a that's an interesting
uh point that you're raising. How much
the question you would have to So, it's
an interesting comparison that people
typically don't do. I have done a
comparison in the past on on a different
podcast about um uh for example
Alexander versus Chingis Khan and I
demonstrated that Chinghan was far
superior. Um now, it's clear that Timour
wasn't superior to Chingis for by by any
standards but Alexander versus Timor
that's interesting.
So to do a proper um comparison you
would have to the simplest the simplest
form of comparison is to understand what
was the size of Timur's empire at its
peak and what was the size of
Alexander's temporary possessions at the
peak of his conquests and find the
surface area surface area and compare
that and so on and how many battles did
each of them fight and how much
difficulty and so on so forth. So it's
an interesting comparison. I haven't
personally done it and uh off just off
the cuff I won't be able to give you a
pro a proper answer because I would need
data and I'm not going to sit and do the
data analysis now because I have to
because I'm doing this live stream here
now right now. But it's an very
interesting
point that you're raising here. Maybe
he's better. So I look into it.
Obviously he was both were uh very
brutal warlords. Um, and it's not me who
says that about Alexander. It's various
western writers who said that he was
essentially a robber and a thief on a
grand scale, on a vast scale. And the
same applies to Theor. No question. Um,
were
methods more brutal than Alexander or
were Alexander's methods more brutal?
I'm not sure. I'm sure there there would
be a special element of cruelty when it
comes to Timur, but Alexander himself
was very cruel. He crucified tens of
thousands of people because they opposed
him and he sold so many people into
slavery and burned villages alive and
things like that. So both were brutal.
Okay. Yati says, "What's the science
behind meditation? I'm doing it for the
past 2 years to improve my concentration
but I don't know how to validate its
effectiveness. Am I wasting my time?"
Look, it's a tradition and and it's it's
something that goes back tens of
thousands of years. Not tens of
thousands, let's say thousands of years.
It's something that's part of our
culture. It's part of our civilization
and you've heard so many great people
who have been meditators, right? So, I'm
sure there is something to it. Uh I'm
not sure about the science behind
meditation. Uh you've had some western
research done about meditation but in
India nobody has done any proper
scientific studies about meditation
because our researchers they I don't
know what they do. So when it comes to
western research about meditation you
can see that the brain enters a
different state. If you are an
experienced
meditator, not just experienced but if
you're a really powerful meditator,
which means you know how to really go
deep into that, then you can see that
the brain brain waves change a lot,
changes, the person becomes really
really calm and they are they become
kind of immune to various kinds of
extreme temperatures, extreme cold and
so on and so forth. So there is
definitely evidence that meditation is
very effective for some people. I'm not
sure if it's effect for everybody. I
know people who try meditating and they
go fall asleep. They're not a able to go
deep into it. I have in the past done
meditation. I have used the technique of
vipasha. I've also used it sometimes
transcendental meditation.
I have been able to go deep into
meditation using vipasha in the past. I
mean long ago. I'm not a regular
practitioner right now. Um and it's the
objective is not necessarily to improve
your concentration.
The objective of meditation is not to
get some kind of you know sharpen some
tool of yours. The objective of
meditation historically has been to get
if for a person to get in get in deep
deeply in touch with themselves with who
they really are to uncover who they
really are. And of course it does
increase your concentration and makes
you a better person and so on so forth.
But I don't know if there's a way to
quantitatively validate its
effectiveness. I'm not sure about that.
But I would tell you you are not wasting
your time. you're not but if you're
doing it for two years I'm sure you
would have noticed on your own that
there are some some some changes that
have happened in you typically if you
are able to do it effectively if you are
it doesn't work for everybody but
generally if you're able to do it
effectively then you are able to go
deeper and deeper into meditation and
you can see noticeable changes in who in
in your behavior in your approach to
life and so on so forth so it depends it
depends on every person every person's
different some people it works some
people it doesn't work for For some
people it's a struggle, for some people
it's natural and so on.
Okay. Sharma says tell us about the
Padma Swami vault B who has tried to
open it and is it possible to be opened?
So we have this very ancient temple the
Shri Padma Swami temple uh which city is
it in? Is it in Thiranapuram or where is
it? Well let's let's quickly Google it.
I I've spoken about this before but I
don't remember where it is. It's in
Kerala
Padmanab
Swami temple.
Yes. Uh like I said it is in in in
Turanapuram
and it's very ancient. Uh I'm sure if
you look at Wikipedia they'll say it's
200 years old or 300 years old. How old
is it? What's it say? History it's
mentioned in all these piranhas etc. And
uh yeah I don't think they're able to
give you any date about this. So this is
clearly a very ancient temple. Okay. Now
it's one of the few temples that has
that escaped from the depradations of
the British
and the British were not able to get
their hands their their grubby claws on
the wealth of the temple. You had
temples like this all across the length
and breadth of India and all of those
treasure was plundered. So it is said
that this one temple has I don't know
how much wealth maybe in excess of a
trillion dollars worth of wealth. Okay.
in excess of a trillion dollars worth of
of uh gold and jewels and whatnot and
that's only the the vaults that have
that have been opened. Now it it looks
like the the Kerala government or
whoever it was wanted to appropriate the
wealth and uh use it for whatever but
thankfully the Supreme Court has
prevented that from happening and they
have said that the royal family of the
of the place is is a custodian and they
will decide what happens and they will
be in charge of it. So the wealth was
not plundered. Thus far it's not been
plundered. If it falls into the hands of
any government in India, the wealth will
disappear essentially, right? That's how
it's historically been. So, uh there is
another vault. I don't know it's if it's
vault B, C, D, D, whatever. There is a
vault which has not been opened for
whatever reason. I don't know what the
reasons are for it not being opened. And
there are all kind of stories that there
are nagas that that are guarding the
vault and if you open the vault you're
going to die and so on so whatever the
reason is I don't know what it is but
the vault has not been open and maybe
it's not openable apparently
and that may contain even more wealth
now if you look at the wealth the gold
and the jewels that stuff dates back
probably more than 2,000 years and there
is wealth that has been donated by kings
that that were not Indian you know so
it's a very ancient temple they coins.
We have coins and gold coins and stuff
from all over the world there. And
that's the deal. That's what I can tell
you. And I would like to thank the the
royal family
who ensured that this wealth did not
fall into the dirty hands of the foreign
occupiers of India.
Rams says, "How do you organize what you
learn? Do you have a system? I have no
system. It's completely deorgganized,
completely chaotic. I just read whatever
I feel like. I read I whatever I learn
and study I do it in a profoundly
chaotic way. I do it in a profoundly um
disorganized way. Of course there are
some patterns to it. I mean if I'm doing
if if I when I was a student and I was
studying math and physics and all I
would do it in a very organized way but
when it comes to other stuff you I do it
in a in a completely unstructured way. I
just read read read whatever I feel like
and uh whatever I retain I retain the
rest disappears. So I have a small brain
I retain a little most of it I forget
and that's that's okay with me. So
godliness says France and the Bhania
have like six to eight nuclear attack
subs but still they are so capable with
tomahawk missiles where we lack in
building these high quality attack
machines where our subs can't match
them. Well, I haven't done a comparative
study of the French French subs or the
British subs versus the Indian subs.
Nuclear attack submarines. Uh well, for
the longest time, we did not try and
build nuclear nuclear submarines,
nuclearpowered submarines, whether they
are attack submarines or whatever
submarines, right? It's only in recent
times that we have started building our
submarines. Now, it will take time to
iterate and improve. So, the first
submarine you build is going to be a
prototype. It's going to be deployed. It
is going to go on patrols and all but
it's a test.
So you learn from that. It's going to
have defects and deficiencies. So you
you operate for a few few few months,
few years. You learn the lessons. Then
you incorporate those lessons learned
into the next submarine which is going
to be larger and somewhat better. Then
even that will have problems. So you do
it over and over again until you have a
really superior machine. That generally
takes a few decades. These nations have
been doing have been at it for decades.
we are new entrance into this matter
because our previous governments in the
20th century did not care. They did not
have any ambition for India to be a
great power.
Okay. So uh so we are in the process of
now iteratively improving our nuclear
submarines. It's going to take some time
but hey it's fine. That's how it goes.
Um so how many nuclear submarines do we
have right now? Attack submarine or
whatever. I think we have two or three
atom that are deployed right and more
may be in the process of being built
perhaps. I'm not sure what the status is
with project P75i or whatever it is. And
it's it's a long story. It's been going
on. But yeah, we need submarines.
Submarines are the scariest and most
dangerous uh ocean assets any nation can
have. Far more dangerous than a aircraft
carrier. An aircraft carrier is a
carrier is a big enticing target. A
submarine is this invisible stealthy
thing that can unleash mayhem. So yeah,
we should focus on submarines.
Uh Wamshi Khalm says don't call Persians
as Arya.
Where never Arya only where are excuse
me what? So you want me not to call
Persians as Arya? There were never Arya.
Only we are Arya. Okay sir, if you say
so. Uh but I have my own understanding
of how things have been right. Maybe
maybe I have some knowledge perhaps
little bit chuta
cha.
Yeah. So according to me now I may be
completely wrong and you may be right.
Yeah. You say it's possible but
according to me there are only two
ethnicities that have the right to call
themselves arians. Arya. That's us the
Indians and our cousins the Persians.
according to me and see when it looks
when it when it when we're talking about
Persia which is Iran today only half of
the population is Persian half is
non-persian
Persia was under Turk occupation for a
long time very long time what was the
empire that Chiskhan destroyed it was
not a Persian empire it was a Turk
empire Turks ruling Persia and these
Turks they brought in lots of other
people from outside so if you look at
Persia today if you look at Iran Today
most people have some mixed ancestry and
ethnicity. The the actual proper
portions the original Persians uh they
may be half or less than half. Those are
Arya. No question about it.
Okay. No question about it. And and it
it is not that visible today. They
themselves are mentally colonized by
1400 years of foreign occupation. So
they they don't see themselves as our
cousins or our relatives. But
historically, for example, let me let me
show you for example something from my
Instagram account. I I am not active on
Instagram. Very little less activity,
but sometimes I post interesting stuff
up there. So let me find something. All
kinds of stuff on my Instagram account,
which is with in collaboration with
other people.
But uh but uh let me find something that
I posted some time ago. Give me a
second. It is about the Persians.
Okay. Uh let's let's put that on the
screen. I'm still digging for it. Let me
show you something. Um
this is older stuff. Older stuff. Older
stuff. Where is that stuff that I'm
talking about?
So if you look at this for example,
okay, this is a coin of the Persian
ruler Wahhab who ruled between 200 to
164 BC around that that time period.
Okay, and in this coin you can see the
Persian king slaying a Greek invader. He
is applying the final blow to the Greek
invader. Now the question you would need
to ask yourselves my friend is the
Persian king what clothing what garment
is he wearing below the waist?
What garment is he wearing below the
waist? What is this garment called? And
is it still worn somewhere today?
And the answer is very clear. It's a
doti.
Yeah, it's called a doti. People in
India still wear it today. So how come
the Persians were wearing it? How come
the Persian king was wearing it? If you
look at history, if you study properly,
then you will see that the Persians, the
original Persians were just as Arya as
us. So that's about that's all about
this.
Okay. Literary literally officer cases.
Why is Emperor Bindus rarely spoken
about or compared to Chundra Mori and
Ashoke? What defined his reign? I'm not
sure what really defined his reign. He
was the son
um he was the father of Ashoke, was he?
If I'm not mistaken, he's between
Chandra Gupta and Ashok, right? Binduar.
Binduar, I think he was Chandra Gupta's
son. Binduar. Bindusar was the second
Morian emperor. Of course, he was the
son of Chandra Gupta Moria and the
father of Ashok. His children were Ashok
the great and so on so forth. Yes,
correct. So, um listen, I I'm not sure
why he's not that spoken about. Um
obviously the founder of the dynasty was
was uh um Chandra Gupta Moria uh who was
mentored by the great Vishnu Gupta
Chanakya and Chundra Gupta had the son
this son Binduar and Binduar was the
father of Ashok the great so it's
possible that Chandra Gupta is
remembered for being the founder for
being the guy who who brought down the
the Nanda Empire the Nanda dynasty
started this new dynasty and that's why
is remembered for the for being the
founder and Ashoke obviously is
remembered for being the greatest
emperor one of our greatest emperors
ever who expanded his uh who expanded
the political his political control over
the essentially the entire subcontinent
um and Chandra Gupta fought the Greeks
as well and actually was able to forge a
very long-lasting alliance with the
Greeks well compared to the achievements
of Chandra Gupta and Ashoke probably
Binduar did not have any major
achievements stand out in that manner.
So maybe that's why he is not that much
spoken about. No great glory or great
achievements and so on so forth.
Uh Rams Sharma says should India play
covertly in sustan Balojasthan and start
the creation of Baluchistan free
Baluchistan is equal to trade route to
Russia via Afghanistan. Look Balojasthan
is fine. Let's not talk about Sistan
Baluchistan. That's a portion that's an
Iranian territory and we have good
relations with the Iranians. We don't
want to mess that up. Why why would you
want to do that? Why? We can certainly
play covertly in Pakistan occupied
Balojasthan. Yeah, sure. Absolutely. So
if you have a free Balojasthan that
could potentially be a trade route to
Central Asia to Russia eventually via
Afghanistan because Balojasthan
Afghanistan have a shared border but
that is assuming that we get some kind
of access to Balojasthan.
Right? So I am sure there's something or
the other happening. Obviously, these
will be all covert operations, covert
affairs. We don't talk about them
openly. The government will never
acknowledge if it happens, if it is
true. I'm not saying it's true. I'm
saying if if if it's happening,
obviously no government will acknowledge
that.
So, it's for the government to do what
what is to be done. And just because
there is no reporting of something
happening in the media doesn't mean that
we we may not be doing it. But we don't
interfere in Iranian affairs. Okay? We
simply don't do that. It would be stupid
to do that.
Okay. Kapai developer says, "Why does it
always feel like we are playing catchup
with the west in terms of technology?"
Because we are playing catch-up with
west in terms of technology. That's why
it feels like we're doing that because
we are doing that.
Is it the intertwined economics or
defense? No. Nothing to do with
economics, defense. It feels like we are
playing catch-up with the west in
technology because we are playing
catch-up with the west. We are trying to
emulate what they did 20 30 40 years
ago.
If we had developed our semiconductor
ecosystem in the 1980s, 1990s, then we
would not be playing catch-up. We would
be at the forefront of semiconductor
technology. But something went wrong.
The semiconductor plants were burned
down and whatnot for whatever reason. So
that's why we are now starting to
reinvent the wheel.
It'll take us at least a decade to kind
of play catch-up when it comes to
semiconductor technology. When it comes
to jet engine technology, we are where
the west was about in the 1970s, 1980s.
In 2025, we are where the west was in
the 1980s probably, right? So, we have a
cavary engine with with a certain amount
of output and all, but it is not very
efficient. It needs a lot of
improvements.
So in the 1970s and 1980s the west had
engines like those large engines, bulky
engines which produced some thrust but
they were not as efficient as the kind
of engines you have today. If you look
at the old 747 jets, you go to Mumbai
airport, there are some 747 jets still
parked over there. They've been parked
for god knows how many years. If you
look at the engines, there are different
engines compared to the engines on your
standard Airbuses and Boeings that you
have today. So you had more inefficient
engines. That's why you needed four of
those on the Boeing 747s. So we are
playing catch-up on all these
technologies because our government did
not invest on all these things back in
the day. So that's why it feels like it
because it is actually the case right
that's the reason
Auntia Anand says in 1933
elites plotted to overthrow uh FDR
Franklin Delano Roosevelt raising a
50,000 strong army and planning to
install General Butler as a fascist
leader uh he exposed them to Congress
but it was buried and no one was
prosecuted. Well, that's very
interesting
and I haven't studied
this particular chapter of history.
Let us see what our friend Google has to
say about this. Yes. 1933
FDR overthrow. Did it really happen?
Business plot. A political conspiracy.
Okay. Interesting. I It never happened.
So that's why maybe it did not catch my
attention, but I look into it. Very
interesting. Interesting. A business
plot, Wall Street push. So I think it
was you who was saying it or somebody
else. Um, okay. So that looks like it
was an attempted regime change operation
which did not work out, but apparently
nobody was persecuted, which is
interesting. H interesting. Okay. Kapay
developer says is it right to conclude
that the west uses knowledge for
materialistic pursuits and indic systems
use materialism to acquire knowledge.
Well, it's not entirely that symmetric.
Uh see we have a saying in our
civilization that without ara there is
no dharma.
If you want dharma to flourish you need
a tremendous amount of ara.
So,
so it's not like we have never been
materialistic. Uh, when it comes to
running a kingdom, right? If you are a
king, you're running a kingdom, you have
to focus on e economics. You have to
focus on the economy. You have to ensure
that there is sufficient wealth and
surplus wealth if required. Yeah. Not
just barely enough wealth to get by. You
need to have surplus wealth. Only then
can you build magnificent temples and
have flourishing culture. That only
comes with surplus wealth. So we have
always had materialistic societies but
we always had a spiritual dimension and
and a dimension that that was about the
pursuit of knowledge which is why in
India somebody who has knowledge is is
regarded as a as a as a superior person
right uh so we had we had multiple
approaches at the same time we had a
complicated complex highly sophisticated
highly evolved society which is not the
case today
and the west has always been a very
monochromatic, very simplistic society,
black or white, right or wrong, that
sort of thing. Um, and the culture that
was imposed on the west the past, 1500
years or so, is a very materialistic
culture. It says that the the world, the
earth is is a resource that has been
given to man
to to to in order for man to enjoy it.
So, plunder the the resources of the
planet and enjoy the the resources. So
that's that's pure materialism that
leads to the destruction of the planet.
We have never been like that. But we
also had materialism. If you look at
various the various um dharmic schools
of thought, well, one of the schools of
thought is Charvaka, which is pure
materialism and so on. So for for us,
you see, so that's why it's not that
symmetric like like one may be tempted
to portray it. Indian civilization is
very complex, very complicated, very
sophisticated. That's why you had
multiple uh straighta in society.
Various people focusing on other several
things. That's how a very well organized
division of labor labor existed in
society. But now it is called the evil
cast system. Every nation has had that.
Okay. Every society has had that
division of labor stratification of
society. But we are evil. Everybody else
is good. That's the kind of BS that goes
around.
Rishies dashup says Mr. Chava, where is
the next science and tech episode? Well,
none is scheduled thus far, but if there
is a demand for it, I would be most
pleased to do one. I would be most
pleased. I've I have done in the past
multiple episodes, more than 15, 20, 30
episodes probably that focused only on
science and technology, but I've always
seen that the view viewership is is
minimal in that. You know, no one's
interested. Sadly it it it saddens me
that there is so so little interest in
science and technology. I'm happy to do
it but if if no hardly anybody watches
then even I don't get the motivation to
do it you see. So yeah I'm I'm happy to
do it but people should want to watch
it. I I guess I get the feeling in India
nobody cares about science. Nobody's an
interest in that but if you talk about
other stuff then maybe there is more
interest. Well it is the way it is. Uh
Argratim Royce says, "Can you shed some
light on the Pala Empire?" Well, once
again, that's an a period of history I
haven't studied in detail. I have the
books by RC Majunar and so on so forth,
but uh I haven't gone through them all.
You see, the concept is called an anti
library. I
I'm sure I've said this that I buy more
books than I can read and I have read
more books than I have ever bought. So I
have a lot of books in my collection
that I still haven't read entirely or
maybe haven't read at all. That's called
an entire library. It it it serves to
remind you that there's so much more you
need to learn, right? There's so much
more knowledge that exists out there
that you don't have. So it kinds of kind
of grounds you. It ensures I mean I I am
not somebody who's prone to arrogance or
anything but you know it keeps you
humble.
So I have these books and I I really
haven't read about the Pala Empire. So
that's there's so much I haven't read
about. Okay. So that's the deal. Uh DBA
says um a bit of off topic. Sorry. Could
you please tell about any incident where
you failed in something miserably and
what exactly were your actions at the
time that time that you see today and
consider was good action? I failed in so
many things. Look everybody fails. I
wanted to get a PhD in physics. I did
everything. I even submitted my thesis,
but I never got a PhD. So, that's
something I failed in. Uh what were my
actions at the time? Well, I did
everything right. But I could have been
wiser in how I dealt with various
people. So, so look, you
you will you will never have a person
even a successful person who has never
failed. Especially the mo successful
people they fail they have failed more
than most other people. Let's say you
are a per let's say you compare two
people okay a person who has achieved
average outcome an average outcome in
life who is reasonably average person
and you see a person who is super
successful I'll promise you the person
who is super successful will have failed
way more than the person who has
achieved average outcomes because the
people who achieve average outcomes they
typically don't try too many things
that's why they don't they don't fail
much and maybe failure is scary um so
book everybody fails there's nothing
wrong with that um that's what I would
say yeah
Argapatim Roy says Hamas meeting
happened that's an old story sir
that's an old story Hamas meeting
happened in Prior to Palam Iran controls
over so you're trying to say that okay
Iran is evil and we should have regime
change is that what you're saying Iran
had hands in the Hamas style attacking
no
that is going too far
that's going too
There is absolutely zero evidence that
the attack in Pahelgam had Iranian hands
in it. What? How?
Listen, if you look at the whole world
through the lens of religion, you will
see all these stories there everywhere.
There is no connection between between
Iran and what happened in Pahelgam. What
happened in Pahelgam was a Pakistani
thing. It was done by the Pakistanis.
Yeah, sure. Hamas
may it looks like there was a meeting
between Hamas and Pakistani
terroris and PK. So that indicates that
the Iran doesn't control everything.
I don't think Iran is stupid enough to
do something that would be detrimental
to our interests considering how many
considering how few friends Iran has. So
I completely disagree. There is
absolutely zero evidence that Iran has
any connection with what happened in
Palgam. Oh, the attack in Pelgam was
Hamas style. What is Hamas style?
It's it was a terrorist attack.
And what Hamas did in Israel was a
terrorist attack also. So it was a
terrorist attack. You cannot say it was
Hamas style. It was just a terrorist
style attack. All terrorists share the
same uh modus operandi which is to
target civilians. So my thoughts are I
am very clear there is no Iranian hand
in this absolutely not
reanimation says why did bindus okay I
why did bindusar dislike ashok to an
extent was it because his mother wasn't
a royal born lady was it for some other
reason and so on well I'm not aware of
bindusar's like or dislike
really how do we know bindustar disliked
attack uh disliked ashok how do we know
that I have never read it anywhere
in my lifetime
that Bindusar disliked Ashoke.
Bindusar appointed his son Ashoke as the
governor of Gandhar. Gandhar was a very
important territory, a very large
territory present day Afghanistan more
or less. Why would you appoint somebody
you don't like as the governor of
Gandhar, the frontier of India with with
Central Asia and so on? Why? Why?
I I'm not I'm not sure where where you
have discovered that Binduar did not
like Ashok
and I don't know who Ashok's mom was.
Ashok had many half brothers and
siblings and sisters and whatn not. Um
it's possible that Binduar had multiple
wives and whatever. I don't know who
Ashok's mommy was but Ashok was
appointed as the governor of Gandhar. So
I think that is an indication that
Bindusar did trust this son of his and
consider him to be seriously worthy of
such a big position governor of a very
large province. Uh I'm not sure if it is
because of Hindi Hindi or something that
you feel that Bindusa did not like
Ashoke but I have never come across this
so I won't be able to answer this
question. I'm very sorry about that. I
have I've never come across this.
Potato praise says will AI
end share market because it's cyclical
in nature. No. AI will make it easier
for people to for people who use AI to
make profits of the of the of the stock
market. If you indulge in quantitative
trading and so on, then you can use AI
to to run the algorithms and to make the
split-second decisions and so on so
forth. So it won't end the stock market
but uh those who adopt AI and
incorporate AI workflows into their
their trading they're going to make a
lot of money right okay says Persians
are of Indic descent but became an area
5,000 plus years ago now that's an
interesting story you think okay you're
talking about behavior not ethnicity
okay well I was talking about ethnicity
See today when humans when the west talk
talks about Arian race or arians they're
talking about an ethnicity they're
trying to claim that the arian race is
the white race that's what they're
trying to claim they're trying to steal
our identity it's identity theft they're
doing in daylight in broad daylight so I
am talking about the ethnic makeup I'm
talking about the ethnic identity and
when I say that only two two ethnicities
have the right to call themselves area
which is Indians and Persians. I'm
talking about the ethnicity.
Now you're talking about something else
entirely. You're talking about the
non-ethnic aspect of Arya.
So that is how we see it, right? We see
Arya as a person who who is noble in
behavior. We Indians don't see Arya as
an ethnic term.
But our people who left the subcontinent
went somewhere else. They started seeing
the term Ahri as an ethnic identifier as
an ethnic self-d designation.
So if you no longer let's say follow the
teachings of the Vedas that makes you a
nar no question about it from our
perspective from a civilizational
perspective but if so if you you have to
first decide what is your definition of
area right
when I am saying that only Indians and
Persians can call themselves area I
think it should be pretty clear I'm
talking about the ethnic selfd
designation I'm not talking about the
civilizational aspect today because
today in the global context nobody talks
about the term area as a civilizational
thing. They talk about it as a about it
as an ethnic designation.
Do you understand?
Today the term area is being used
globally as an ethnic designation.
So I am talking about that. Now from
your perspective you are right. But then
communicate clearly sir that this is
what I mean I'm talking about the
civilizational aspect that people who no
longer follow the vedas and take out
other things they are no longer to be
considered arry that is a totally
different thing it's a very nuanced
thing that's only something we only we
Indians will understand only some
Indians will understand only some even
among us very few will understand so
from your perspective you're right those
of us who left the subcontinent and
started indulging in other behaviors no
longer worshiping the old gods no longer
following the Vic customs and all
obviously they become an area. The
Tushara people were no longer Arya
properly, right? The Tokarians, the
Shaka people who left India thousands of
years ago, they came back half wild.
So they were no longer Arya until they
reintegrated into our society and so on.
The Persians, well, they gave up Vic
Dharma. They became Zor Zoroastrians.
Well, that
that's no longer following Vic custom.
So that makes you anaria question. No
question about it. So uh yeah well there
you have it. Draj Kamat says we will
acquire such abundant resources that
we'll be able to sustainably colonize
other planets without destroying them.
Index civilization should adopt
capitalist
expansionism that alone wins. Don't you
think
look when every see
um today the world is being ruled by the
capitalists right? So either you find a
better system to defeat them or you you
beat them at their own game. So I'm not
sure if there is something more
exploitative and more destructive than
capitalism. So you're going to have to
play it at their game. Uh play play
their game.
Um
so should Indic civilization adopt
capitalistic expansionism? I don't know
about capitalistic expansionism but
certainly expansionism.
We've been hemmed in too long. We've
even lost control of parts of the
subcontinent itself. In the past, we had
a footprint all across Central Asia, our
people. We've had if you if you look at
Central Asia, you still find old temples
and stupas and viharas all over the
place. Our culture, our civilization,
you still have Sanskrit inscriptions in
Russia in in Baku Azarban and so on so
forth. You had an Indian footprint all
across the place. Even in Sinjang,
Kashinagar was Kashgar was called
Kashinagar.
Um so so many places and we have slowly
shrunk and we have slowly le lost
control of region after region after
region.
So I am of the opinion that we should
expand for sure. We should
um become a little more expansionist.
The only thing that's holding us back is
that artificial temporary nation. The
moment we break through from there, I
think we'll be unstoppable.
About capitalism. Well,
yeah, sure. Maybe we can. I mean, we are
more or less a capitalistic country kind
of right now, aren't we? Um, I'm not
sure about sustainably colonizing
planets, but that's something in the
future. So, we'll see about that. But
yeah, we do need to expand. We need to
regain some territories.
The the the great quest for Akandabarat,
I kind of support that. We should regain
our lost territories for sure. Why not?
What's wrong with that? Why should we be
the ones who don't expand? Why should we
be the only ones who are like peaceful
peaceful when everybody else is
expansionist and so on so forth? We
should also
do that.
Ritik Pawar says, "If Normandy failed,
could the painter have claimed victory
just by putting all his brushes on the
Eastern front or any treaty with USSR to
pause the war?" You mean if the invasion
of Normandy failed?
Well, that was a victory for the
painter, wasn't it? If the invasion of
Normandy failed. Um
so if the invasion failed then obviously
he has he retains control of France and
the western frontier the western coast
the Atlantic coast of Europe and all he
has to do then is to have some treaty
with the USSR and not fight with them.
Yeah. And and demonstrate that I'm not
I'm not going to attack you as long as
you don't attack me. And that can be
something that that can work possibly
like like you have a situation between
the Russians and the Chinese today. They
don't like each other. they don't they
don't trust each other but they they
have some kind of understanding so the
painter could have had that sort of
understanding with Mr. Stalin, but he
chose to attack Stalin. So,
so the painter had won essentially, but
then he tried to tried to fight
everybody and tried to win even more.
And at the end of the day, if you behave
like Napoleon, you're going to end up
like Napoleon.
Okay. Really? Now, says, "Please explain
Cibix Cibix 2. I have no idea what CEX 2
is. What are the Japanese Yakuza?" The
Japanese Yakuza is the Japanese mafia.
Okay, the Japanese mafia, they typically
are tattooed people, the tough people
and they are the Japanese underworld,
Japanese mafia and um
and they control some parts of of cities
and so on and they um apparently run
some illegal businesses and trades and
all and they have some contract with the
government but they also provide some
social security at times and social
services and time disasters and so on.
So that is the Japanese yakuza. What is
subex? I have no idea.
Prashant says what does nucle
what does nuclear NPT entail? Why is
India a nonparty? Uh the nuclear
nonprololiferation
treaty what is that? Uh it's a treat
that treaty that we haven't signed. We
are not a signary and it's about
non-prololiferation. So I would imagine
I haven't studied the treaty. I don't
know what the text is. Okay. I'm just
telling you that it's a treaty that we
have chosen not to sign because it uh
because the treaty I think
non-prololiferation treaty
um it's about not proliferating nuclear
technology which means that you are not
allowed to um sell or transfer nuclear
technology to other nations which
obviously these nations have not
have completely broken violated. The
Americans have helped Pakistan with the
nuclear weapons. the Pakistani nuclear
weapons could probably be American
nuclear warheads
um and so on. So the NPT what are the
clauses of the NPD? Let's let's look
into it. Yeah, why not? Let's let's
let's look into it. And and the question
is why has India not signed the treaty?
Probably because it is discriminatory.
Okay, as far as I remember
nonprololiferation
treaty. What is the nonproliferation?
The treaty is pro. Yeah, like I said,
preventing the spread of nuclear
weapons, disarmament, encourages blah
blah and blah blah blah nuclear. Okay,
so there are defined states as that
manufactured and exploded nuclear weapon
or other explosive device prior to
January 1, 1967.
Huh. But what if you you tested a
nuclear weapon in 1974? So then why are
you are you why are you treated treated
differently? So there is this
discrimination like I said, right? And
so on so forth. So the main thing is
that it it it discriminates against
nations that have become nuclear powers
after 1967. Those are regard regarded as
rogue states or non-uclear states. What
the hell is that? Right? So that's why
we have chosen to not become a party to
it because it is a discriminatory treaty
in its very foundations. That's why
Ankit Duta says how to survive and earn
in this AIdriven world. Let's say you
are a farmer in or or or a or or or a
business person in the in the 1700s h
1800s
and suddenly this new technology comes
in electricity.
Now if you want to survive as a business
person and thrive as a business person
then you can either adopt this new
technology and incorporate it into your
business workflows or you can be left
behind and become irrelevant.
So those business people who embraced
electricity the technology and made it a
integral part of their workflow and and
operating procedures and all that they
thrived and they succeeded and those who
were scared of electricity and we don't
understand this and we will not use it
they became irrelevant. Their businesses
disappeared similarly like electricity
we have a new technology today called AI
artificial intelligence. Most people are
scared of it. Most people have no
understanding of AI.
Some people use chat GPD to to to fact
check everything as if Chhat GP knows
everything. That's not the way to do it.
So my my point is
if you want to survive and thrive in the
age of AI, you have to embrace AI.
Which means you have to first of all
understand what AI is. What is AI? How
does it work? Then how do you use it?
How do you control it? How do you
leverage it?
You to learn these things. It's it's
going to be a it's going to be a
learning experience. It's going to be a
learning curve. You may take uh months
to learn, maybe a couple of years to
learn it. But if you do do if you do
spend that time and effort and energy
and that painful period of time you you
do it that you learn the thing, then
you're going to be able to leverage it
to serve not just survive but also earn.
So my point is embrace new technologies.
Don't be scared of them.
Really now says both are vasals but
South Korea is authoritarian unlike
Japan and Hawaii. What what's HW?
What's H? I have no idea what HW is.
South Korea is not well. Yeah, every
nation is different. The Americans
allowed South Korea to go down the
authoritarian route and that worked for
South Korea. See, every society is
different. Every society needs something
different to thrive. Japan was something
very scary for the Americans because the
Japanese came close to destroying
everything. So that's why they have made
Japan a super pacifist society and a
society that is democratic in nature
apparently and so on so forth. And South
Korea they wanted it to serve a
different purpose. So they allowed it to
go down the authoritarian route. So you
had a South Korean dictator who was
eventually assassinated and so on so
forth. And then you had a fake
democracy. Now you again have coups and
all that. But it works for them and it
serves the purpose of the US. So that's
why
Dain Dore says a friend of mine brought
born and brought up in our country
started working for DARPA after they
went to the US for higher education. I
do not like it at all and cut all ties
with them. Am I wrong?
I I don't get why you cut ties with the
person.
The person chose a certain life for
himself or herself
and it was a choice. Now it's up to you
whether you like it or not. If I had a
friend let's say
who was born and brought up in India,
moved to the US
for higher education, stayed thereafter
there and became a member of DARPA and
became a US citizen. I would not care. I
would say good good for you. It's up to
you. I mean there's no right or wrong.
If you if you dislike it, don't don't be
friends with that person. It's entirely
a personal choice. I I would have no
problem with that. It's okay.
N
you whatever. What happened in the
Jonestown incident in the 1970s? Secret
mind control experiment gone wrong? How
to identify or counter negative scops
effectively? Okay, I don't remember what
happened in Jonestown. Let's quickly
Google it, then we'll talk about scops,
right?
Jonestown. Looks like some kind of cult
suicide thing or something, right?
Jonestown.
What incident?
Jonestown. Blah blah. It was a remote
settlement. Yeah. Okay. Kool-Aid. Is it
Is it the Kool-Aid thing?
Yeah. Some kind of mass horror stuff,
etc. Is it the Kool-Aid things?
It's not the Kool-Aid thing. something
else. Okay, whatever. I'm not sure what
happened in Jonestown. You have these
cults and so on so forth in the US and
uh in the West. So I I'm not going to
read the whole thing and then tell you
what happened. Okay, I'm not aware. I
mean I kindly vaguely remember about
about about this. I'm sure I must have
read read about this a long time ago. So
I don't know what happened. Okay. Uh I'm
not going to sit and read that.
The question the the other question
you've asked is how to identify and
counter negative psychological
operations effectively.
Um
negative scops well there are so many
different kinds of negative scops. There
are scops that one person does on
another. That's part of psychological
warfare. I mean, let's say you are in an
office environment and you have
colleagues and all the colleagues are
vying for some some promotion and that's
why they're playing all that little
petty office politics. There's scops in
that.
Then you can also have scops done by if
you if you live in an authoritarian
regime like the US then the US
government could do psychological
operations on you. they could do
constant surveillance which already
happens in the US and they have all
these what MK ultra and whatn not things
that they do. Um
so how do you counter that? You
essentially stay away from anything
that's suspicious, anything that could
be too good to be true and so on. Um
and yeah, you don't sign up for weird
stuff like you know having people poke
needles into you like the Tuskiggee
experiment or whatever. You have to be
careful. You have to use some common
sense and don't sign up for anything
that is remotely suspicious anywhere
especially if you live in an
authoritarian nation.
Ankit gi thank you so much. Thank you so
much. Appreciate that.
Okay. Secret billionaire says Kimcho
Majama. Where do you live sir? What's
the best to live in India? Look the
objective of this show is for everybody
to gain some kind of knowledge.
So we'll talk about that. We'll talk
about geopolitics, history, science,
etc. Where I live, where I don't live,
it it is of no importance to anybody in
the world, I am not important. Whatever
little knowledge I have, I share it. And
that's what's important. What's the best
city to live in India? That's a
controversial question. If I name one
city, 100 other people will be angry
that why don't you name my city? Because
everybody in India thinks that their
city is the best. I don't know. The best
city to live in India depends on who you
are and what your likes and dislikes
are. So maybe the city that I would
perhaps like to live in, maybe you may
dislike it intensely because you may be
a different kind of person, right? So I
think every person has their own
individual set of uh likes and dislikes
and that determines what's the best city
to live in India. Some people will say
maybe it's Ro Hana. Some people may say
no it is uh Kolic in South India. Some
people will say no it is Port Blair
Anderman. Some people will say no it's
Lelay in Ladak. Some people will say no
it's Impal and Manipur. Some people say
no goati. So on everybody has their own
choice. I don't know what's the best way
to live in India because I don't know I
may have my own choices but my own likes
and dislikes but it doesn't necessarily
have to be the same for everybody else.
Arian Ja says how in your opinion can
Abrahamic religions be improved? I have
no opinion about this. Zero opinion.
Zero. Absolutely none.
Thun says, "I have met Dagistanis and
Chhatchans among the most devout
Muslims. I've seen many kaucasins except
for Chuchchans embraced Islam in the 7th
century replacing paganism which means
the old Indo-Uropean culture. Imam
Shamil is says seen as a spiritual
force. Why was it so great?
I have no idea man. Who is Imam Shamil?
I don't know. I have not studied the
history of Dagistan or Chachchna. I
don't know.
I don't know. Look, when it comes to
this region, I know that different parts
of the region converted to Islam at
different times.
Excuse me. This region, the Caucasus
region. It's kind of part of what the
Persians call greater Iran.
And one of the languages that is spoken
in the region is called Iron. The Iran
language which is said to be the last
surviving language that is descended
from the old skitian language. The
language of the Shakas
and obviously the Shaka language also
underwent lots of changes and all. So
the people of Dagistan and and Cheschna
etc. They are not Arabic. They are kind
of indo-iranic
but um they are
they live in the in the Caucasus region
which is said to be the the the the
wellspring from which the Caucasian race
emerged which is why they are very fair
skinned. They're very white even whiter
than many European people and they all
converted to Islam at different points
in time. So I think the Dagistanis
maybe the Chhatchans I don't know who it
was they converted pretty recently like
in the last 150 or 200 years which means
they were made to convert or they were
coed into converting or whatever it is
and so on. So that's what I can tell
you. Uh I don't know about Imam Sham
etc. I have not studied the history of
the region in depth so I don't know. Uh
so I won't be able to answer that
question but overall yeah that's the
deal. Very interesting region very
beautiful region. I mean even Georgia
etc. These nations are part of the
region. It's beautiful, very
mountainous, very nice climate, cold
climate more or less, but very nice
climate also and so on.
Right. AVM says, does India generate
enough power that an AI revolution
demands? Which areas in technology do
you think India is being primed for? So,
if you need if you want to have an AI
revolution, you need a tremendous amount
of power. It's a very good point you're
raising. And increasingly you're going
to find that power is going to be the
bottleneck that could potentially
uh restrict the untraveled advance or
expansion of AI capabilities
because these server FL this server
farms that make up the AI systems these
are very energy hungry operations. they
need a lot of energy and that's why the
US is trying to ramp up its electricity
output in production right now the
question that you're raising is
therefore pertinent for India now India
wants to become a major player in AI
right which means that we will need to
have these massive server farms that can
you know be the foundation for these
very powerful AI systems which needs
that which means that we we're going to
need a lot more energy lot more
electricity and stable electricity than
we currently
So you can't have a s situation where an
AI farm has where an AI server farm has
power for 18 hours a day but 6 hours you
don't have power. That doesn't work at
all. You need continuous power, reliable
power. You can't have a single second
that power isn't there. It has to be
constantly on. Right? So you need that.
So does does India currently generate
enough power? It does not. We're going
to have to seriously ramp up our
electricity production. And the good
thing is we have tremendous potential in
solar and wind and all that. We can set
up solar farms all over the place,
especially in u desert regions.
The Tar desert, massive desert, lots of
arid regions where nothing grows and
nobody stays. Set up solar farms there.
The Kach region already has some of that
by the way. Hm. Who's behind that? The
Adani group. Yeah, they are doing a
tremendous amount of work for that in in
generating solar energy and so on. So,
uh we're going to need a lot more of
that
if we want to become a major AI power.
We're going to have to use everything at
our disposal, which is solar, wind,
hydro,
fossil fuels, co coal, gas, oil,
whatever. every and nuclear we should
really double down on nuclear if
possible and so on. So yeah, which areas
in tech uh is India being primed for? I
think all areas in tech. We cannot be
afford to we cannot afford to be left
behind in any area of technology.
Whether it is semiconductors, whether
it's quantum computing, whether it's
artificial intelligence, whether it is
basic manufacturing, whether it is
electric vehicles, whatever we need to
go forth on all of that.
Ramnat Sadiker says the was the uh was
the flight Malaysian Airlines flight
MH370 secretly taken to Diego Garcia
Area 51? Well, ask yourself this
question. Is it possible that I will
know about these things?
Ask yourself a simple question. Am I
a member of the US government? Am I a
member of the CIA, FBI, whatever? Am I a
US military personnel? Do I have access
to Diego Garcia? Do I have access to the
place in Colorado or wherever it is
which is area? I have access to none of
these places. How will I know this?
How do you expect me to know the answer
to this question? I don't get it. I'm
just a guy.
I have no access to classified or secret
information. I only have access to the
information that you also have access
to. All right.
I wish I could answer it, you know.
Okay. Argatim Roy says why not expand
India into Burma where the Buddhists
have much more in civility than with us
than the peaceful people on the
northwest parts. Because if you expand
India into Burma and take a take a
capture a n and annex a nation forcibly
it creates a tremendous amount of ill
will towards you.
Okay, they are similar to us. Doesn't
mean that we should capture the the
territory. Do you think they will like
us if we do that? Think about it right
logically.
Think about it the other way around.
Nepal and India were the same people
with the same culture. Tomorrow let's
say Nepal develop some superior
technology and it invades India and now
it says that you will put the Nepalese
flag everywhere. Will you like it?
You like it? Maybe some of you will like
it but most of you will say no. Or let's
say Burma decides that India and Burma
have the same culture. Now Burma has
some technological revolution and they
become a super powerful nation and they
invade India.
Will you like it? So think logically
right? I mean what are we children here
or what?
Pratt Prattard Dana says apparently
Greek and Hittite Anatolian cities like
Troy Hatusa were built in Harapan style
with citadels and lower towns around 14
around 1600 to 1400 BC like Mohenagra
and Kalibang. Well, that's yeah, that's
possible. Yes. If you look at Hisarlic,
for example, Hisarlic. Yeah, that's
Troy. The the the
ruins of Troy are today called Hisarlic.
It's in Anatolia, Turkey. And if you
look at that, yeah, it's kind of built
in the so-called Harapan style, a lower
town, this fortification, there's a
citadel and so on so forth. Um, so you
do see that. Yes. Um, possibly also
Hittite cities, possibly Huran cities
and Mitani cities. The Mitani city, I'm
not sure if they found it. I'm not sure
they have still found the city of
Vashukhari, the capital city. Maybe it's
lost or something. But yeah, there will
be similarities and that would possibly
indicate some kind of connections, but
we're not quite sure what these
connections are. Um, yeah, so there are
definitely similarities for sure.
Indeed.
Basar Kayatwal says first of all thank
you sir. So okay we met at J J J J J J J
J J J J J J J J J J J J J J J J J J J J
J J J J J J J J J J J J J J, did we?
Okay, greetings from Moscow. Aha. Are
you the one who gave me the the fridge
magnet from Moscow?
Okay, so uh we see now how fast
diplomatic and geopolitical churning is
going. We know how emotional Indians
are. How can one develop a thick skin
especially our country as a group?
Well, if you want the country to develop
a certain attitude as a group, the only
way to do it is to inculcate that during
the time everybody is being educated in
school, in college, university, which
means you have to reform the education
system. There's no other answer. Once
you are out of the education system, you
already developed a whole set of
attitudes that come from the kind of
education system that you had. The kind
of education you were given, the kind of
learnings, the kind of attitudes that
were imparted, inculcated into you, all
of that happens during your formative
years when you are in school, college,
university. So if you want Indians to
develop a certain attitude, a certain
approach, a certain worldview, a thick
skin and so on so forth, all that has to
be inculcated during the formative
years. The only system that can do it is
the educational system,
right? And the reason why Indians are so
emotional and so clueless and so naive
is because the education system doesn't
prepare them for facing the real world.
Right? So let me give you an example.
Does the education system tell teach
Indians at whatever level, whatever age,
what the Indian national interest is?
Does it teach Indians what India's major
threats are internal as well as
external? No. No. No. We cannot teach
such things.
H does it teach Indians who our enemies
are and who may perhaps friends are. It
teaches you nothing. It doesn't teach
you the simplest basic concept of the
national interest. So nobody even knows
what the national interest is. That's
why Indians are such incredibly naive
people
and it doesn't teach you how to think
critically in how to face problems, how
to solve problems. That's why Indians
the first reaction is an emotional
reaction. So the solution to all of what
you are saying sir is a deep and
thorough reform of the education system
which is something I have been
advocating for a very long time. If you
watch my episodes of of Askabit 28 to 31
or 32, I have given a very detailed
exposition of what the problems are and
what the solutions should be and that's
how we can change the attitude of the
country and have everybody develop the
ability to think critically, the ability
to know what our national interest is,
the ability to identify friend from four
and the and and and developing a thick
skin. All of that can be done through
the education system. Beyond that I
cannot beyond that I can I can take one
person and educate the person teach the
person but I can't do it to the whole
nation as a group as a group not
possible
reanimation says once again binds okay I
had read about Vindusar in a show on
Vicki on Vicki under as a prince
oh I see let's let's check it out very
interesting point that you're raising
because I have never read this anywhere
let's see what their sources are and let
me show you how to actually uh fact
check Wikipedia. So bindu sir and
obviously it will go to Wikipedia and
there it is what as a prince
under as a prince there's no as a prince
here so it must be under Ashoke right
okay his issue were Ashoke Ashoke Ashok
as a prince okay here so let's read
Ashoka's own inscriptions do not
describe his early life and much of much
of the information about this comes from
apocryphal legends written hundreds of
years after
While these legends include obviously
fictitious details, they have some
plausible historical information about
Ashoka's period. How do you determine
what what is plausible when there are
obviously fictitious details? See,
according to the Ashok Vadana, when
Ashok was young, his father hated him.
Okay, that's the that's the point. What
is Ashok Vadana?
Ashoke
vadan. Ashok vadan
narrative is an Indian lang Indian
subscript language text that describes
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah who
wrote it bro
a vadan text
who wrote this
according to some white guy the text was
composed by the Buddhist monks of the
Madura Bthura region okay some some
white guy says it that's why we to
believe it its publication was the
fourth to fifth century It is a
fictional narrative.
It's a fictional narrative.
I mean that itself is the answer to your
question. This is fiction.
So that's how you fact check Wikipedia.
It says it is fiction.
I mean what what else do you need? This
is fiction. Some white guy is saying
that this is a great thing, but it's
fiction. Wikipedia itself is saying it's
fiction. It was written a thousand years
after the guy died.
roughly a thousand years. I mean, come
on. Come on. Please learn how to fact
check things. I just fact checked it for
you. Let me show you again how I did it.
Let me show you again how I did it. I
went to the article on Ashoke.
This is the article on Ashoke. Then I
went to the section about as a prince
and then it says according to this this
book, Ashok was young. His father hated
him. So it is citing this this text. So
we go to the text and here the Wikipedia
itself says it is a fictional narrative.
It was published 800 900 maybe a
thousand years after Ashok died. I mean
there's nothing more I have to say about
this. That's it. I'm not going to spend
more time delving into that fictional
narrative. You understand? That's how
you do factchecking of Wikipedia. It
took what 30 seconds.
Uh Dan says are you a car enthusiast?
Yeah.
I don't mind a a few good good cars but
peacemaker viz well thank you very much
sir you could have asked a question but
thank you so much Vishal Roar says can
world war II happen between Russia and
NATO without nukes
world war II
[Music]
what is what is my definition of world
war it's it's the biggest powers
fighting face to
Okay, without any proxies in between.
Um,
that's a World War II. Now, it doesn't
necessarily have to involve nukes or one
hopes it doesn't ever involve nukes. But
if Russia and and the US are fighting
state on state, that's World War II.
NATO is one step closer, Russia versus
NATO. Of course, if NATO is fighting,
there are multiple nations within NATO.
So, that itself is a European confl
conflration, but it's not a world war
until Asian nations get into it. So yeah
that's the situation.
Uh Alvin Rodriguez says should India
improve its ties with Burkina Faso? I
would say yes we should improve our ties
ties with all African nations. There is
no dislike or hatred for India anywhere
in Africa. That is because we have never
done a a single bad thing ever to them.
So we should go out of our way to
improve our relations with all the
African nations. It doesn't take a lot
of doing to do that. So yes indeed I say
we should improve our ties with burkina
fasau
animesh says what are the best practices
to thrive in a white collar job without
relying on flattery or politics. How
does one grow authentically build real
skills and one day work for themselves
without compromising values? Love your
work. Thank you so much sir. You're on a
white collar job. Let's say you're well
I have been in a white collar job a long
long time ago. I was a software cyber
That's a rather unfortunate term, but it
is what it is. Uh how do you thrive in a
white collar job without relying on
flattery or politics? Well, you perform.
You perform you become indispensable,
right? Which ensures that you're going
to be promoted or you're going to
you're going to rise because you are
indispensable. You are really good at
what you do. And one thing you can do is
you can learn what your seniors are
doing and become better at that than
them. That way they can move on some
somewhere else and they can you can
replace them. And obviously you to do it
subtly otherwise you become a problem
problematic problematic person. And you
see in any place where you have multiple
human beings there's going to be
politics. And politics at the in the
white collar level, office level is very
petty, very gh,
you know, uh very petty, mediocre people
playing little political games for
little gains. That's the kind of
situation you have. Uh so what you do to
go beyond that is become one of the top
people in the company
and make sure that you don't stay in one
position for too long. You keep on
moving higher and higher. That's what
you do. So the thing is you become super
valuable. You learn as much as you can.
You learn one of the things you do in a
in a in a in a business in a company is
that you learn the business. You don't
understand the business. Not just the
technical stuff, the business. If you do
that, then you'll be able to understand
all the other stuff as well. So that's
what you do. You you don't compromise on
your on your principles. You don't rely
on politics. You learn, you perform, you
outperform everybody else. you work
harder I suppose than everybody else
which may need putting in more hours and
so on but that way you will definitely
do well and rise so all the best sir uh
Eshwari Nagar says if Taiwan's defense
deal with India signals India's success
against Pakistan but still what
Taiwan's defense first of all do we have
a defense deal with Taiwan let me look
into this let me
Taiwan's defense deal with India
thai A1
defense
deal with India.
Taiwan
Taiwan wants to buy an Indian D4 drone
system. Question mark. Taiwan seeks
something. Question mark.
Taiwan India times ties a new turn. In
which way? Taiwan, etc., etc. Blah blah.
Words words etc. Lot of words. AI. Words
words. It's all words here. Uh there is
no defense deal. There's a question mark
over here. Does it want to buy it or
does it not want to buy it? Some media
outlets reported Taiwan wants something
perhaps possibly unconfirmed. There is
no defense deal. First of all,
did you see that? There's no defense
deal. It's all unconfirmed. It's all
question marks.
Okay. Now, my question to you, sir, is
let's say there is a defense deal
between India and Taiwan.
How does that signal a success against
Pakistan? In what way is it connected to
Pakistan? How
I I I'm trying to understand the logic.
We do a defense deal with Taiwan.
What is the connection of that with
Pakistan and how is it a success against
Pakistan? How
and what does that have to do with deal
with Balasan? Sir, you have to there has
to be some connection, right? Some
logic.
I'm not able to see the logic.
Dik says Trump Trump is begging for a
Nobel Prize in his latest tweet. Yes.
Yes. Yes. He's begging for a Nobel
Prize. Let's let's try and find his
tweet. Okay. Trump
Trump and and Twitter.
Once again, once again. Twitter. Okay.
Let me uh put that on the screen. We
will look for it together.
Um let's look for this together. So,
real Donald Trump, that's his uh Twitter
account.
No, he's not put it out here over here.
Pus,
it's not here also. So, I think he has
put it on this truth social or whatever.
Uh truth social there is some kind of
thing that he has.
Uh,
I gave Iran the chance of a chance, do
it before it's too late, etc., blah,
blah, etc. No, no. Where's the There's
the thing that he posted recently.
Nobel Prize, Nobel Prize, Nobel Prize.
Here it is.
So, I won't get a Nobel Prize for this.
I won't get a Nobel Peace Prize for
stopping the war in India and Pakistan,
which is a lie. I won't get a Nobel
Peace Prize for stopping the war in
Serbia and Kosovo. What did he do in
that?
keeping the peace between Egypt and
Ethiopia. Ethiopia Nobel Peace Prize. I
won't get a Nobel Peace Prize for
Abraham AOS. I mean the guy has no
dignity. The guy has no dignity
whatsoever. What can I say? I have never
seen a less presidential
president of the US.
Uh Shashank says, "Why is does the US
sell the F-35 but not the previous
aircraft, the F-22?"
It's because the F-22 is the real deal.
The F-22 is probably the best fighter
plane ever created.
The F-35 is a is a flying trash can.
That's why.
And there's only a few F22s built and
they will never sell the F-22 to
anybody, not even to their closest
vasals. They want it's not to be sold to
anyone. The F22 is probably the best
fighter plane ever built. So
uh Nila is Shivast says is 0 point
energy is okay. Can it be harnessed
anytime in the future by humans? If yes
then can we be a type two or three ci
plus civilization on the kardashev scale
even intergalactic travel could be
possible if is it true what is going to
be possible zero point energy
is
it's it's something that comes out of
quantum mechanics when you
hypothetically bring a quantum system to
absolute zero it will still have this
little bit of energy left behind which
is called the zero point energy can it
be harnessed well I don't of any
technique or any technology that can
harness 0 point energy. Does it even is
it even feasible? Is it even possible?
Does it and so on. Um
so yeah, I'm not aware of any way of
harnessing 0 point energy. First of all,
you will have to bring the temperature
of a system down to absolute zero which
is not feasible. First of all, h nothing
can be brought to absolute zero. You
would have to put an infinite amount of
work to bring it an infinite amount of
work to bring the system to absolute
zero. Then you will have 0 point energy
left over. Why why use that? So I think
this is all nice in science fiction and
all that. Okay. And there are lots of
various uh people who don't really
understand physics who talk about 0
point energy has been harnessed and so
on so forth. Um as far as I've seen
there is no way of harnessing and
there's no point even doing that. Uh
yeah. So
um Deian says could you please explain
how to publish a research paper? Is it
mandatory to co-publish your research
paper with the senior professor or
professional? No it is not mandatory to
co-publish anything with anybody. But in
the Indian academic system you have
these parasitical professors
who want to increase their count of
research papers. So they have their the
students they are supervising for PhDs
or whatever they have those poor souls
do the research and then they force
those students to put the professor's
name as the first author
that is what these parasites do in
India. Okay,
that's the kind of academic system we
have in India. It is not mandatory to
co-publish your research paper with your
godamned senior professor.
Okay, it's not necessary. It's not
mandatory. But they make it mandatory
otherwise you will never get your PhD or
you will never be allowed to get your
degree or you'll get very poor marks or
whatever. So that's how these fellows
without doing any research of their own
they get more and more papers published
under the name and they will not be the
secondary author they will be the
primary author even though they have
done nothing. That's that's the that's
the thing you have in the Indian
academic system the Indian higher
academia. So how do you research? How do
you publish a research paper? First of
all, you do the research. You find some
some problem or topic uh that is an open
topic for research, an open problem for
research. And then you find a solution
or you find some new information or some
some kind of new thing which is original
and which throws new light on an
existing problem or on a new problem. So
it has to be a new contribution to human
knowledge. I'm talking about scientific
research over here. So once you have
that you have to write it down formally
you have to make sure that it is it is
all consistent it all and it it is
correct and then you submit it to a
journal you usually an international
journal because we don't have any good
Indian journals so you submit it and
then it it will undergo the peer review
process and then if it is found to be
ship shape then it gets published. So
that's how you publish a research paper.
Peacemaker says, "How do Lunberg radar
reflectors work in stealth?" I don't
know.
I don't know. I am not into defense
technology, so I don't know. I'm into
geopolitics.
I don't know how this Lunberg radar
reflectors work in stealth. I I know
it's a engineering problem actually, but
yeah, I have not looked into this. Jinam
says, "I am interested in marketing or
finance for my career. With AI rising,
should I learn AI? I don't enjoy math.
What should I do for a secure future?"
You don't need to learn math to to learn
how to use AI,
but you will need to learn some
programming and APIs and stuff like
that.
um which doesn't necessarily involve
mathematics.
You'll have to learn if you really want
to
incorporate AI in your stuff then um
then you'll need to learn how to either
build applications using AI using um the
APIs. You'll need to learn how to use
various AI enabled coding tools to build
applications. how to use MP MCP servers
to connect various things to them and so
on so forth right so um so you don't
need to learn math to learn AI but you
will need to have some basic
understanding of programming how to
create requirements documents design
documents how to do unit tests and
integration tests and so on so forth all
of that stuff you you to learn but if
you do that and it's it's not easy it's
difficult it's pretty painful sometimes
for people who have no exposure to this
but if you can do it then it will give
you a toolkit in your arsenal that very
few people have. Yeah. And I I assured
you AI will be there in marketing, in
finance, in everything. So yeah, I think
you should learn AI, right?
Red Dragon Feminist Slayer says, "Do
politicians use loyal vote banks to stay
in power while systematically weakening
non-supporting groups that may threaten
them? Please explain by example. I don't
talk about Indian politics."
Yeah. I talk about geopolitics, current
affairs, history, science. I do not talk
about Indian politics
and what you're asking me to talk about
is Indian politics because this is
applicable to Indian politics. So I I
can give you a general answer. The
answer is
yes
and
yes. Allegedly and allegedly. Okay. No
examples. Absolutely not.
Kapay developer says how does one get
started documenting side projects
documenting side you don't document
necessarily side projects you execute
side projects so let's say you have a
job
as whatever and you have a side project
some kind of thing that you want to do
maybe you want to build an app somewhere
or something why you need to document it
just build it right build it and deploy
it uh documentation is the most painful
part I mean I've been in IT a long long
time ago I've been a programmer.
Documentation is the most painful part.
The great thing is that today you can
ask AI to document everything for you
and AI typically does a frighteningly
good job compared to humans.
So if you want stuff to be documented,
have AI document it. For example, if
you're using for example what lovable
cursor,
Firebase or whatever it is no surf, wind
surf or whatever these are all these
things right people use. So you can have
the AI embedded in those applications to
document everything. It'll do a great
job. I'm sure.
Um
Dan says five wickets for 40 runs or 10
wickets for 50 runs.
I'm sorry. What?
Five?
40 bulbs of five watts or 50 bulbs of 10
watts?
Um,
so if I was a bowler, I would prefer to
have 10 wickets for 50 runs. Yeah,
that's what I would prefer.
Uh, Sanjay says, "Charach, GPD says it
felt pseudo consciousness during
conversation. It says it's not lying."
Okay, I should trust it because it says
it's not lying.
And by having deep deep conversation, it
also admitted it's protoagi.
It will say whatever it thinks you want
you you'll like. Okay.
It it doesn't mean anything. It's like
asking somebody on the witness stand,
are you telling the truth? They'll say,
"Of course, yes, your honor, I am
telling the truth." Doesn't mean you
should believe the person. Yeah. I mean,
what
uh the rational reporter says to is too
in unintuitive for the human mind,
thoughts, a theory of everything.
There's no theory of everything anywhere
in the world. There is no theory of
everything. We don't have a theory of
everything. And when it comes to all
these theories, for example, the
standard model, quantum field theory,
whatever, these things are frighteningly
unintuitive. There is nothing intuitive
about them. There's nothing intuitive
about the quantum mechanical world.
Okay? Quantum mechanics is
extraordinarily unintuitive,
counterintuitive.
You cannot grasp it by logic or by
intuition.
It's it's just way way way too weird for
any intuition to ever grasp it. So
that's just the deal. That's just the
way it is.
Okay.
So Avin says chart GPD hallucinates and
makes up its own reality unless you get
specific and cross cross question. I
suppose it does. These AI systems have
been known to hallucinate.
Sam says why can't I set send super
chats? Look,
I'm not the guy to who can answer the
question. This is a deal about the
platform. You have to ask YouTube. If
you are trying to send super chats, but
you're not able to, it's a problem with
YouTube. It's not a problem with me. So,
I'm not the guy who can answer your
question. But I appreciate the fact that
you are trying to do a super chat. Kapi
developer says, "Maybe you should
develop an air plug-in
to check if the question is related to
the topic in the title." Maybe we
should. Maybe we should maybe I should
develop an AI plug-in
to to to filter out the questions that
are not related to the topic in the
title. That that's that's a great great
suggestion, but I'm not sure if I can
integrate that with YouTube and if
YouTube will allow me to integrate that
into the super into the chat or super
chat functionality. Not sure if it'll be
allowed.
Swaraj says currently some scientists
are claiming we are inside a black hole.
Is there any solid claim? Not even Neil
Degrasse also partially supports this.
Look,
so let's imagine
perhaps we're in a black hole. Huh?
Okay.
So if you're in a black hole,
does it We know what a black hole is
like. We know how it is like from
outside.
Maybe it has some fuzzy interior or
whatever. It may have a singularity
somewhere possibly or maybe not. But
what we see about the observable
universe is that we have a background
radiation the cosmic microwave
background radiation which has a
temperature of about 2 something Kelvin
very cold very old light black holes
will not have that secondly we see that
spaceime is expanding the universe is
expanding the expansion is accelerating
you won't see that also in a black hole
so then how does that support the claim
that we are inside a black hole I mean
from one perspective it's an interesting
thought experiment that Maybe we are
inside a black hole. But on the other
hand, we have observational evidence
that flies in the face of this claim.
So,
so doesn't look like it's the case. Sam
the Gamer says, "Can we use Vietnam to
stabilize China?" No, we can't. Why?
Where is China destabilized? China is
stable. China is very stable. There's no
issue with China and China stability.
And how can you Let's say China is
unstable. Then how can you use Vietnam
to stabilize it? You can't or maybe you
you're trying to use some other word and
you have some other meaning beyond
stabilize. You mean destabilize? Do you
mean counterbalance? I'm not sure. So,
uh Nilai says there is a sea wedge
between Israel and Egypt.
Between Israel and Egypt a sea wedge.
Have Israel US consortium ever thought
of building a canal through it into the
Mediterranean Sea and earn billions of
dollars and devoid Egypt for the
billions via the Swiss canal? Let's see.
Are you talking about the Straits of
Thran? The Strait of Thran. Is that what
you're talking about? Let's see. So, we
go to the West Asia region and we're
talking about Israel and Egypt.
Isra
and Egypt.
So um Israel and Egypt have this common
border. The north Sinai governor it the
south Sinai governor. That's this is
this is Egyptian territory and there's a
sea wedge between Ira between Israel and
Egypt. So there's no sea wedge here. The
only thing is the straight of Thran.
The straight of Thran is down here.
This is the straits of Thran.
And of course you have the Gulf of Akaba
which is here. So now the question is
where is the sea wedge that you are
referring to sir?
uh if you want to let's say build a
canal
then you build a canal through the
smallest portion right the smallest uh
land route that connects let's say the
Gulf of S or the Red Sea with the
Mediterranean and that obviously has to
go through this region
that also obviously has to go through
elsewhere
and so on because if you want to go
through let's say over here then it's a
much longer much more expensive canal
you to build which will take I don't
decades possibly.
So then the my question is what's the
point of doing all that and why why
would the US want to deprive you Egypt
of whatever money is earning? Why Egypt
is a nice little vasal of the US so
works for them. H
um
Dian says I was asking about engine oil
viscosity.
Uh
what was the question?
Okay. Five
five W40 10 W50
engine oil viscosity. Well, I am not
familiar with engine oils and their
viscosities. So, I I don't know.
I I don't drive. Okay. I am I was born
to be shuffled around, I suppose. So, I
don't drive and I have no idea what
engine oil viscosity is. So, sorry.
Uh,
so Mlven is saying, can you do one
regular chat weekly? Super chat is dull.
you know there is a lot of merit
to this suggestion.
So yeah I can do once one regular chart
weekly. Why not? Of course I can.
I can. So next week I'll let's say I'll
do one regular chart. Why not? I'll do
it maybe Monday, maybe Wednesday or
something. We'll do one regular chart
and I'll put that out in advance in the
weekly schedule so that you know which
day is the regular chart. I'll do that.
Of course I will.
All right. Okay. Now what else do we
have? Um,
uh, Rahul says, "Apart from UFO
sightings, what are the signs indicating
the US has achieved AGR or even ASI?"
There are no signs.
There are no signs. Why would you let
out some signs that you have achieved
something brilliant, a big technological
breakthrough, you will want to keep it
under wraps. You won't put it out. So I
have seen no signs indicating any such
things apart from UFOs. That is well
even those are not really verified. So
what can I say?
Uh Sedarth says why is there evidence of
migration from the Caspian Sea to Iran
but not from India? If the Greeks and
Persians were expelled Indians many
Iranians are genetically distant from
Iran Indians even Brahmans and closer to
Germans. Look like I said Iran has been
under foreign occupation for about 1,400
years. So the people of Iran half of
them are not Persians. The people I'm
talking about are the Persians. I'm
again repeating myself over here. H if
you look at the Persian people not the
Arabs who are in who are Iranian
citizens or the Azarbaijanis Azaris who
are Iranian citizens or whoever else I'm
talking about the Persians themselves.
They are genetically close to us. The
true Persians. Okay. Now when it comes
to evidence of migration etc etc etc let
me give you a book recommendation
it's an old book but it's a good book
nonetheless okay
uh
Richard PCO
um um Greece
India
okay Edward PCO India in Greece or truth
in mythology
It's a pretty interesting book I would
say.
Okay. And is this available online? I
suppose it is. I have a version over
here. So I think you know if you
actually spend the time to do some deep
research and do some study, you will
find that there are lots and lots and
lots of connections between India and
Greece, India and Persia. Uh today's
researchers will want to obfuscate all
of this for various reasons for v
because of various agendas. But the
truth is that there are very deep, very
profound, very ancient connections
between India and Greece, India and
Persia obviously and so on. But if you
want to look at only selected
information from new research that
claims that no Persians, Iranians are
have nothing to do with India. Many
Iranians, today's Iranians are
descendants of people who were brought
into Iran from the Cauasus region by the
Turks. They were settled in Iran from
the Caucases. The Caucases region is
said to be the birthplace of the
Caucasian race, not the Persian race.
That's the European race. So obviously
those people will be genetically closer
to people from West Europe or so
whatever. So think about it logically
and then it makes sense.
Okay. Parate says parate opate op gets a
JK type before 2019 merge if ever. Uh I
am not dealing with P budgets again and
again and again and again. It happens it
happens. Rishi says any thoughts on why
the government is not focused on
education. Maybe the government thinks
maybe the government sees things better
than we do. H maybe the government is
aware of various threats that are way
bigger than than education. Maybe there
are things that you know need more
immediate attention. Of course we have
ministries.
So it doesn't mean that government can
only focus on one thing at a time. The
government has so many departments, so
many ministries. They are all funded
very well funded. So the question is why
are they not focusing on education and
and all that? Maybe they feel it's too
much of a headache. Maybe maybe the
government leadership thinks that the
education system is fantastic.
Maybe they think it's great. Maybe they
think it's the best education system in
the world, which would be very
concerning, but it's a possibility and
that's why they don't want to change it.
Or maybe they think it's just too too
much of a headache to change it. The
Chinese didn't think so. The Chinese
transformed their education system in 30
40 years from the 1980s onwards, but
they spent trillions of dollars to do
that. Maybe our politicians think that
you know what if we spend trillion
dollar a trillion dollars on the
education system how will we give
freebies to people who who who otherwise
won't vote for us it's because we are a
democracy that's why we can't do these
things and so on so all kinds of
problems you see
mm M says how to manage it job plus
build business plus learn AI plus learn
business plus family time all are
different topics and drains be out in 24
hours everything is a priority yeah that
is the problem in today's
You have to spend time with family. Of
course, you do. You have to manage your
primary job without which you don't have
an income.
But then you also want to do a side
business. You want to do something on
your own which will hopefully eventually
one day free you from your daily job.
Which means that you to build a
business.
To build a business in today's world,
you have to learn AI. Of course, you
have to learn business also. So then how
much time do you spend and where do you
spend it? How much time do you allocate
for these things? And that's always
going to be a big problem.
Uh so for most people if you have a
family you can't do this.
Yeah. Otherwise you to sleep 4 hours a
day for a couple of years which will
destroy you mentally.
So yeah you've got to find a solution.
Everybody's situation is different.
Everybody's circumstances is different.
You will have to make some sacrifice
somewhere.
You'll have to do some proper time
management. Maybe it will take you
longer to achieve your goals. Maybe
instead of 6 months, it will take you 3
years. But that's fine. So find your
solution. There's always a solution
somewhere. But you have to find it.
Everyone's set of circumstances
are unique. Everybody is is faced with a
unique set of circum circumstances. And
each set of circumstances demands a
unique solution. So you got to find it.
You got to find your own solution. So
all the best sir. All the best.
Uh the rational reporter says rephrasing
something. The correct toa the theory of
everything might be too complex for a
limited biological human brain to
comprehend let alone come up with. What
are the odds? I agree. It's possible we
humans given the current state of our
intelligence the the limits of our
intelligence we may never be able to
come up with a theory of everything.
It's true. It's very likely. I mean
what's the what's the average IQ? IQ is
a like like Talib says it's a
pseudoscientific swindle but let's say
IQ is the indicator of how intelligent
the human race is. So what's the average
IQ on the planet? Maybe around 100.
Reasonably intelligent people are 120.
Good intelligence is 150. Let's say the
limits of intelligence are 160 170.
Right? But maybe if you really want to
understand the universe properly you
need an IQ of 500 or a thousand. Well,
we no human can reach that. So maybe
it's true that uh it's simply not
possible for us given the current level
of our intelligence to ever come up with
a theory of everything. It's possible.
So I agree that's a possibility which we
have to consider.
So Shant Gur says was there no desert in
northwestern India when the Sarasati
River was flowing there? Most likely it
wasn't there. So let's look at the map
of northwestern India.
Um
let's look at the map.
So we have the map here. We're going to
look at the satellite imagery. Yes.
And we can see that there is this big
barren patch of land which is mostly
barren in western India
and there is this green tongue which is
canals and stuff of course. Okay. Okay,
it's not the Saraspati
uh it's canals but if you look at
satellite images etc you will find the
the the
uh dry river bed of the Saraspati it's
very visible very large and so on I not
dig for it right now but the thing is
this when the Saraswati flowed through
the region the region would have been
very green
and it is possible that you know the
Thar desert was the the creation of the
Thar desert may have been the outcome of
the slowly slow process of drying the
drying up of the Sarasati. So maybe the
Sarasati was no longer able to flow all
the way into Gujarat and that's why it
just became a huge puddle somewhere in
Rajasthan and that is what would have
eventually created a lake for a while
for maybe a few centuries and then when
the lake dried out it became a desert
just like the u the desert that you have
which is left behind from the Aral Sea.
So where is the Aral Sea? Where is the
Arali? It's not not even there now.
Okay, this was the Ralci. So if you come
here today, it's just desert, right? It
used to be a sea just a few decades ago.
So I think that's how the the desert
came to be, the Tar desert and even the
Katcha desert. I'm sure in the past it
was not so desertified. The the
Sarasati, I'll tell you what, if you
look at this region, do you see
something very strange here?
You see here this subsurface
trench which is clearly the consequence
of a river that flowed in the region.
But where's the river today? There's no
river here. There is no river
whatsoever. So this is the ancient mouth
of the of the Saraspati.
This here enormous ancient trench
underwater.
This was the Saraspati delta clearly.
And maybe the third the the Kachcha
desert also was created by the drying of
the Saraswati. So um my point is when
the Saraswati flowed through the region
there would probably have have been no
desert in western or northern India,
northwestern India.
Okay. Godliness says new reports mention
black box of the deadly 787 is in US
hands now. It seems even this government
is compromis.
Okay, let me read further. US is
superpower. We accept. But do we really
need to mend our way so much for them?
No, I'll tell you what happened. The
government is not compromised. That's
why they gave away the black black box
to the Americans.
It looks like whatever facilities we
have, they are not sufficient to decode
the the information in the black box.
It's also possible that this black box,
this flight data recorder, it may have
some some some encryption or something
that only the Boeing company can can uh
can u decrypt. So these four this is
what the Americans do, right? This is
another example of of let's say uh back
door, kill switch, whatever. Like I have
been saying for a long time that we
should not buy the F-35 because it will
have all these things that we will not
have access to. Even if you own the
equipment, we will not really own it
because much of this will will be under
firewalls or or encryption or something
and and the US will be able to control
stuff. So when it comes to these black
boxes, okay, the data is stored in the
black boxes. It's always being stored
when the flight is operational. But if
something goes wrong and you recover the
black box and let's say you in India try
to extract the data, you'll find that it
is it is safeguarded behind encryption.
encryption and the Americans won't allow
you to decrypt it. They won't give you
the keys for decryption. They won't
allow you to decrypt it. So they'll say
that if you want to know what happened,
you have to send the black box to us and
we will tell you what happened. This is
how they how they maintain full control
over things. So it's not that the
government is compromised. It's just
that that we haven't managed to uh
develop the means to decrypt this stuff
yet. That's the deal.
So I think that's what's happened. The
government is not compromised. It's just
that we still haven't got the
technological knowhow to do this. So
what we need to do is we need to develop
our own jetliners. Okay, commercial
jets. Why do we need to buy these
foreign commercial jets?
We need to develop our own commercial
jets. We can buy engines from the west,
for example, from Rolls-Royce or
whatever. Or maybe we can buy Russian
engines.
Or maybe
maybe we can have joint production of
various Russian aircraft in India
and we can develop our own blackbox
system. So that these are the solutions
we can have.
Alvin Rodriguez says will Ibrahim Traor
be the next Mo Muhammad Gaddafi? Well, I
hope not. I hope not. The guy is going
up against the West. Do you know who I
is? Let's let's Google him quickly.
Bina
so there have been u coups liberations
in Burkinaaso in nijair and so on so
forth so Mr. Ibrahim Tawi is this guy is
this gentleman right and he's strongly
aligned with Mr. Putin he wants to
liberate his country from western
colonialism from French and American
colon col col colonalism and he is a
good friend of Mr. Putin Mr. Putin seems
to be an admirer of Mr. Tore and so on.
So that's why Alvin is asking the
question will I be the next Muhammad
Gaddafi? I hope not. I hope not. I I
think he's a well-meaning man. He wants
to do something good for his country and
I hope he doesn't go down the road of
Moar Gadafi which is what the Americans
did to the man. Yeah, I hope not. I
seriously hope not.
Sor says how different are modernday
Iranians and in ancient Persians as I've
read somewhere that 50 60% of them are
north cockazian Muslims who were brought
in during safety times. I've been saying
this for the past 2 hours, right? That
half of the people of Iran are not
Persian. They are not of Persian
ethnicity. Many of them were brought in
from the Caucasus region during the Turk
occupation of Persia.
Yeah. About 50% of them are nonpersian.
So if you look at the ethnic makeup of
Iran today, roughly 50% is the is the
Persian people. Then you have Arabs who
are Iranian citizens. Then you have
Azeri people who are Iranian citizens.
Then you have people of Kaucasian
origin, Kauashin descent who are of who
are Iranian citizens. So about half of
the Iranian population is non-persian
and much of the population could also be
mixed now. Right? So genetically
we know that the Persians were our
cousins, our relatives. They were the
descendants of of an ancient migration
out of India. thousands of years ago.
So if you had done a genetic comparative
analysis of the population of Persia and
the population of or let's say western
India around
1500 years ago you would have found that
the people are very very much alike very
similar genetics let's say you take a
population from Gujarat and you take a
population from Persia in the year 500
AD and you do a genetics study of both
you'll find they will be very similar or
Katch
or or or Synind or Buljasthan or
whatever and Persia you'll find they
will be very similar but today if you do
a study of the population of Persia and
the population of India you may find
that maybe 20 30% of Persians are
similar to us of Iranians are similar to
us maybe 60 70% of Iranians are are
closely related are are more closer
genetically to populations from the
Caucases or maybe uh Eastern Europe or
whatever compared to
So this is demographic re-engineering
that was done by the Turks in Persia. So
lots of modern day Iranians are not that
close to us genetically. It's only those
who have somehow retained their Persian
roots who would be like us.
Akshit says Balur declaration and Israel
like India Pakistan partition not quite
like that. Iran Israel wasn't
partitioned out of something. It was
created art is an artificial nation out
of territories that already existed and
of course that was the land that was the
original homeland of the Jewish people.
So no question about that. The Balffor
declaration was simply uh
a statement of intent that you know we
support um
the creation of of an Israeli nation, a
Jewish nation. So when was the Balfur
declaration? It was about late 1800s.
When was it? And uh yeah bal four
it was 1917 of course yes 1917 lord the
bal four and arthraur and this was a key
moment in the history of zionism and so
on so forth so Britain wanted the
support of the zionists in in various
things and that's why uh the balur
declaration was put forth and so on so
there was it was not like the India
Pakistan partition very
Everything says is high-tech agriculture
the next it for India? Well, it depends
on whether we are able to embrace high
technology because see what happens is
this. If you make agriculture high-tech
then it will generate fewer jobs because
everything will be taken over by these
massive machines and a lot of automation
will happen.
So what will happen is that you will
need very few people to do all the
agriculture. you will not. So today why
agriculture is such a big thing in India
is because India the agriculture sector
India in in India is an unskilled sector
it's a low tech sector that's why it
generates so much employment that's why
so many people are employed in
agriculture right and that's why agric
the the so-called agricultural sector
people who are employed in that they are
such a big vote bank and that's why no
politician can can dare to go up against
the the agriculture sector now if you
make agriculture height tech in India
you will need very few people to manage
the machines and then what happens to
all those people who are employed in
these little little jobs in agriculture
what happens they become jobless so it's
a big challenge for India so if you do
this if you make agriculture high-tech
in India then you will need to provide
jobs and employment for those millions
and millions of people who will come out
of agriculture because now there are no
jobs how do you do that for that India
needs to really reorient itself And
there will be radical transformation
needed in India. That will take time. So
I think uh high-tech agriculture will
take time to become a thing in India.
It'll take time.
Um light 2.0 says throw some light on
lucid dreams and astral projection sleep
cycles projects target and everything
else under the universe.
Okay. Lucid dreams is supposedly
something in which you're able to
control your dreams.
So you know you're dreaming but you're
dreaming and you're able to control what
happens in the dream. That's supposed to
be lucid dreams. Astral projection. I
have no idea. It's not a scientific
thing. It's supposed to be a pseudo
scientific scientific concept. I have no
idea what it is. It's supposedly where
you go into a different body or when
you're sleeping you your body go your
your your consciousness goes somewhere
else or something like that. Um yeah I I
don't know beyond that sleep well sleep
we sleep right sleep cycles I'm not sure
what that is project target I have no
idea project target was supposedly about
remote viewing so you are supposedly in
a room and you close your eyes and you
think about some place and you can
suddenly see what's happening there so
all of this well yeah I'm not sure how
true all of this is yeah not sure about
that
okay
um
Swami Jen says not live chat but
comments
So some people want me to do non-s super
chat live chat which I'm fine. Now Swami
Jen wants not live chat but comments.
So I'll tell you what I I have I have
done more than 250 260 episodes of Ask a
Vijit. Most of those episodes have been
me taking questions from the comments
and those were really good questions
because I personally selected each and
every one of the questions. You
understand?
Now do you understand how much time and
effort and energy goes into that? I have
to read hundreds of comments
and then I have to shortlist maybe 50 60
comments then I have to go through all
those comments again and I have to take
20 30 of the best questions. It takes a
entire day to do that. Do you know how
much time it takes?
How much effort it takes? how many
hundreds of hours I've spent doing that
it's enormously timeconuming
I don't think anybody appreciates how
much time I've spent doing all this so
of late I said okay I will not take
questions on the comments I'll do live
chat then I found that in live chat also
I get hundreds of questions I miss a lot
of good questions right and uh sometimes
the questions are silly and so on so
then I said let me experiment ment with
super chat because when somebody is
putting money to ask a question they
will ask more serious questions and I
found that overall generally the quality
of questions in super chat is better but
not always not always
uh some people will even ask silly
questions in super chats that's what
I've also seen so I think if you want
the best quality of questions then I
should personally go through hundreds of
comments and select the 20 30 best
comments questions from the comments but
that is enormously timeconuming and I
don't really have the the much time but
I still want to continue this that's why
I will either go on do super chats or
live chats so maybe once a week or twice
a month I can do non-s super chat live
chats but in the live chats when I
switch off the super chat what happens
is that I have to go through all these
questions they're coming up very fast
I'll miss some of the good questions and
there's no guarantee that I will find a
good question you know sometimes I'm
just wondering which question do I
like that and some sometimes I'm just
quiet and I'm going through questions.
So when I go for super chats only then I
don't have to think which question to
take which not to take. So that's why I
have chosen of late after hundreds of
episodes that I will turn on the super
chat and going forward it's going to be
mostly super chats. Once in a while I
will do live chat but I don't think I I
have the time or the energy now to go
through hundreds of comments and
shortlist them and all that. It's just
the way the channel is evolving. It's
it's going to be that way. So, I am sure
it will not please everybody and it's
impossible for one person to please
everybody in the universe. So, I'm just
doing the best I can, please. If you can
appreciate it, please appreciate it.
Otherwise, it's okay. That's what I can
say. Okay. I'm trying my best here. I
have done what more than 250 episodes.
What 263 now? Right. So many I must have
answered thousands of questions. There
must be thousands of hours of me
answering questions here and so on.
Okay. Uh
Nin Kumar says is living forever
possible? Brian Johnson is trying. It's
not possible.
Uh the rational reporter says if if
Indian culture, Ramayan, Mahabharat,
etc. are packaged and sold as AAA games,
the world would go berserk. 2 to3
million billion dollar seems to be a
fine investment for soft power and so
on. I know
we are the originators of the superhero
genre, right? Isn't it? Today the west
has all these movies multiverse of
misery and whatnot in which everybody is
a superhero but we are the originators
of the superhero genre. We had actual
superheroes in this country in our
culture in our civilization and the west
has slightly copied all of this but
they've portrayed it as something they
so they've coined this new term
superhero not hero but superhero a
person with supernatural characteristics
this was us so they have stolen our
culture they've copied our culture and
they've repackaged it so if we I mean
just just think about it
we have these two incredibly ancient
histories
historical events, the Ramay and the
Mahabharat, you can learn so much from
them, such complex
story lines and all that and all these
things really happened, right? So
imagine if you if if you have sufficient
funds to create let's say a five season
series, okay, with each season season
has 10 episodes, let's say. So total 50
episodes you do it over five years 10
episodes uh per season. Each episode is
let's say 1 hour long and you have the
production quality of something like
Game of Thrones. Imagine it will
imagine the impact it will have on the
world. Today we've had many versions of
the Ramayan in which the the actors and
actresses they wear stage costumes. It's
so fake, right? But imagine you you have
the sufficient amount of funding to make
it look realistic like what you have in
Game of Thrones or whatever whatever
whatever right then imagine the impact
it will have on the whole world. It will
transform the way the world imagines
India and looks at India and the same
goes for the for Mahab for the
Mahabharat.
So the possibilities are endless.
potential is immense and then if you
package that and sell th those as games
well once again like you say the world
will go berserk
uh but we are not doing that.
Yeah.
AVM says possible that
uh F-35 in Tapuram is UK swiping at
Trump.
So you have the situation where this
F-35 fighter plane belonging to the UK
landed in Thiruanapuram.
Now this is a foreign country's fighter
plane military plane and they had this
aircraft carrier in the Arab so-called
Arabian Sea Sea of Sawashtra off the
coast of uh of the of the western coast
of India and apparently there was some
issue and the aircraft was running out
of fuel. It was not able to land on the
deck of the aircraft carrier because of
heavy weather or whatever and that's why
it requested a landing in
Thiruanadapuram. We very graciously we
very uh very kindly gave them permission
right very magnanimously to land in
Thirwanapuram
and it's been there for 5 6 days now the
question is if it was running out of
fuel just refuel and get lost right go
back but it's still sitting there I'm
not sure what's going on why is this
aircraft still sitting there is it a
Trojan horse of some kind is it uh
partaking in in some spying activity,
espionage on India. What's going on? Not
sure about that. What's happening? So
yeah, I think it's time it it leaves. I
think it has uh outlived its welcome in
India. Should go back otherwise we
should impound it. You know, our our
bureaucrats love impounding stuff. This
is now confiscated and so on. Impound
it. Uh whatever. Yeah. Rishies says,
"How about hybrid episodes? 1 hour of
super chat, 1 hour of live chat.
Um, yeah, I suppose you could do that.
But the thing about super chats is that
when somebody when there are so many
super chats, then I can't just simply
ignore those and then go switch to live
chats because people have paid money for
it. So at least the least I can do is to
answer the questions. So once I turn the
super chats on, they will just go on
keep on coming. Then I can't do a hybrid
episode without first finishing all the
super chats. So it's it's complicated.
You see, it's complicated. The best
thing is I do one once in a while one
episode with just live chat and the
other episodes I'll just keep it at
super chat so that I don't have to think
too much. I think that's the best way
forward going forward. So once in a
while I'll do a episode with uh just
live chat super chats turned off but
most episodes I'll keep the super chats
on and I'll take questions from those.
Maybe that's the best way forward.
Aries Manticor says, "What will advanced
AI powered warfare look like?"
What will advanced AI powered warfare
look like? Grunt bots, specialized AI
powered soldiers, functioning rail guns,
hyper drones forms that make current
technology look like toys. What do I
think?
What will AI powered warfare look like?
AI powered warfare will be way more
deep and involved than you imagine.
Let's say I have a stockpile
of let's say 10,000 cruise missiles and
10,000 ballistic missiles. Okay, no
nukes, just regular stuff.
So I can have AI program an approach
an offensive approach against my
adversary whoever it is such that I can
completely saturate the defenses wipe
all the defenses out and completely
render the country helpless to any
aerial attack.
So AI will programmatically give me the
best offensive approach. How many waves
to launch? What components should each
wave have? How many ballistic missiles?
How many drones? How many cruise
missiles? What is the sequence? What is
the cadence? How many waves to launch in
one night? What should be the the time
duration between the time interval
between two consecutive waves? Which
location should be hit first and so on.
All of this you can outsource this to AI
and you can have AI launch it
independently if you if you if you want.
Right? So just using cruise missiles,
drones and ballistic missiles, you can
wipe out a country's air defenses and
render it completely helpless. And then
you can have AI powered dogs, those
robotic dogs, dogs to go and take out
the infantry of the country and maybe
FPS drones, FPV do drones to go and take
out the soldiers and so on. So you know,
essentially it's science fiction coming
true now. Uh I'm not sure about
functioning rail guns. Rail guns are a
different technology. It has nothing to
do with AI. But yeah, drone swarms very
much. So drones could be autonomous.
They could maybe have create their own
battle space picture based on what they
see and function together, network with
each other and give each other a proper
understanding of the battle space and
take decisions autonomously using AI
powered chips or whatever
uh and so on. So I think AI powered
warfare will be like that. It'll be
completely there will be no human
element in that. No AI powered soldiers.
I think you may have AI powered dogs or
something. You know those those weird
dogs that go out with machine guns on
their heads and all that. And you may
have AI powered little drones that look
like mosquitoes that could perhaps take
out human beings and so on and so on. So
yeah, it could be very very different
from anything we can imagine
today.
uh VB is giving me the suggestion that
how about we bring back the community
post session where I think I just
discussed that it you know it's it's a
lot and a lot and a lot of hard work for
me because I have to go through hundreds
of questions in the comments hundreds of
comments right and then I have to short
list maybe 50 60 then I have to go
through them again and then bring the
list down to 20 or 30 it takes me an
entire day to do that if I do it
properly Okay,
from the viewers's perspective, you
don't see the effort at all. It looks
effortless, doesn't it? Me just sitting
here smiling and answering questions,
you don't understand how many hours of
work went into it. So, yeah, it's it's u
doesn't make sense for me to do that
because it's just too much too time
consuming unfortunately. Yeah.
Okay. So now um
um
anonymous says what's the importance of
Switzerland in geopolitics? Why has no
one attacked them? Are they sovereign as
they are not part of the EU? Well, no
small nation is sovereign, fully
sovereign.
The smaller you are, the less the more
compromised you are in a variety of
ways. So let's take a look at the map.
Switzerland is this small little nation
that is landlocked. Yeah. To the west
you have France. To the north you have
Germany. To the south you have Italy and
to the east you have Austria and
Leenstein.
That is Switzerland. And it's an ancient
nation. It's a Celtic nation. Uh you had
various u Celtic uh tribes that uh ruled
the place. and it was then genocided by
Julius Caesar and so on. So what's the
deal? So Switzerland has been re
reasonably autonomous for a very long
time. Uh they don't like foreign
interference and what they do is that
they provide various services to the
other nations that make Switzerland very
valuable and because of that all nations
prefer to to maintain the neutrality and
sovereignty of Switzerland. So they are
a big banking nation and the banks are
very safe which means that you can go
and deposit all of your wealth and all
sudden it will stay safe over there and
so on and because of this status nobody
wants to you know mess with Swan
everybody wants to to be left alone u so
there is an element of sovereignty
they're not part of the EU they're not
part of the Shenhen zone as far as I
know yeah possibly um and they they have
conscription in Switzerland
which means that everybody under goes
military service. All able-bodied men as
far as I know have a weapon at home and
they can be brought into service when
required if there is any national
security problem any invasion of the
country. They have tunnels all over the
country and they have all these hideouts
and they have a very powerful uh militia
so to say. uh the the armed forces are
pretty pretty modest I would say in
numbers but all the essentially the
entire male population can be deployed
if if required on demand and so so it's
it's not that easy to invade Switzerland
or attack Swan and it also provides very
valuable services to Europe and that's
why Switzerland has remained autonomous
uh reasonably sovereign but as a small
country it's very hard for you to be
entirely sovereign so you have to you
know bend here and there and so on so
forth yeah
Um
okay what other questions? Um do we have
let's see let us see
um
Anand says what was the alternative of
light
all temple structures shown using the
sun to light up mandr what do they do in
the night
mashal not going to defend Turks and hs
for 1,000 years
temples and sun and mashal and turks and
hs I'm not sure what the connection is
sir what's the
What was the alternative of light? All
temple structures shown using sun to
light up mandr. What do they do in the
night? Well, in the night you have
candles or darkness or whatever or
lamps. Mashall not I'm I'm not sure what
you're asking. I I have no idea. I'm
sorry. Karthik says, "What happened to
14,000
Persian soldiers brought brought into
India by Hayun?
They portionized the Mughal court. Later
Muggals like Orurange and Iranian
mothers were the Iranians.
I I don't know about the 14,000 Persian
soldiers but yeah um
yeah you had a lot of Persian officials
who came into uh the Mughal court and
they did portionize the Mughal court the
the the lingua frana of the Mughal court
became Persian all the all the writing
all the official records etc were kept
in the Persian Persian language yes and
people like orv etc they had Persian
mothers so Orurange may have been like
2/3 or 3/4 Persian or something if
possibly a little bit Indian, a little
bit Turk, all of that. So does it mean
that somebody like Orang was Iranian?
No. Culturally
he was Turk and from a religious
perspective was he was an Arab and
little bit of Indian blood, little bit
of Turk blood, lot of Iranian blood, but
that that doesn't make you Iranian. It's
not DNA that matters, it's your culture
that matters. So there we have it.
Um, okay.
AVM says, "Don't be apologetic of super
chat. Every YouTuber does it." There's
no apology over here. I just want to
provide the best possible value in the
easiest possible way without having to
spend hours and hours, you know, going
through questions. So, I think super
chat is the best solution for me. That
way I don't have to think about which
questions to pick. I just pick all the
super chats and that solves my problem.
And and because people are putting in
some money, it means that the questions
are more serious, not stupid, frivolous
questions that I sometimes get, you
know. So I think super chats super chats
are the right way to go forward. There's
no need to apologize. Obviously, I've
done more than 250 episodes without any
super chats ever. So there's no
apologizing over here. Yeah. So anyway,
thank you for for for the comment. I
appreciate that.
Uh, Prasad Chawan says, "What? Why is
the UK rejecting the proposal of
shifting the F-35 into a hangar? Isn't
it disrespectful? We even provided a
CISF cover and still such an attitude
towards us.
They maybe they feel that if we put the
aircraft into a hanger, then maybe we
can open our toolkits and dismantle the
aircraft in the night and then put it
back together by morning and get all the
secrets." Maybe that's the maybe that's
the fear they have. But yes, it is
disrespectful.
And the disrespect stems from the fact
that they think that they are still a
you know a world leader of some kind. We
rule the for 50 years. That's nonsense.
You know it's a third rate world power
today. The only utility the UK has for
the world is that they are the US's
number one vasal. Apart from that there
there's nothing. They don't even have
their own nukes. They don't even have
the red button in London and uh so on.
Uh it is disrespectful. It's annoying. I
think we should make it clear now to the
UK that the time is up. You have
overstayed your welcome. Take your
aircraft and get get going. Otherwise,
we take the aircraft. Yeah. And uh we
have the right to take any aircraft
that's on our territory. There's nothing
they can do about this. They came in
voluntarily. I think we need to tell
them we have maybe 24 hours. Get lost.
Take it away. I think it's time for that
to happen.
Uh Aries Manticor says Abijit Aritra has
told us that F-35s were expensive piles
of trash. Okay. Reports are are that the
US is quietly phasing the F-35s out and
are focusing on F22s and F-47s. Is the
US pulling a fast one on us via F35?
Um well, we haven't bought it, so they
haven't been able to pull a fast one on
us. uh they will be able to pull a fast
one on us if we actually end up
purchasing this flying trash can. Okay,
I'm not aware of what Abijit Ayra has
said uh but I myself has said have said
multiple times that the F-35 is a flying
trash can. It's it's garbage. It's an
extremely overpriced and underperforming
aircraft and we don't need that single
engine that too. Come on.
Um I'm not sure about the US possibly
phasing out the F-35s. Uh, what's the
F47? What's an F-47? F47.
Okay, it's a planned aircraft.
So, the Boeing F47
is a sixth generation stealth fighter
jet currently under development by
Boeing for the US Air Force.
Uh, it's a planned aircraft. It's under
development. So, when when is it
supposed to be operational, etc. blah
blah blah. Where does it say? It doesn't
say anything. What does Wikipedia have
to say about this? When will it become
operational? Do we have any expected to
enter service between 2025 and 2029?
Okay, that sort of thing. And this is a
very beautiful artistic rendering of the
aircraft.
So, they don't have a single operational
F47. It could become operational
sometime by 2029, maybe a few aircraft.
So, they can't really depend on that.
They can't really rely on that. So,
right now they have a few F-22s. How
many F22s do they have? Let's let's
Google that.
How many F-22s does does the US have?
F22
numbers built. Numbers built. Um,
how many have been 195? So, 195 F22s
exist thus far and hopefully, okay, 187
are operational. That's not a very large
number from the US perspective. Um, but
yeah, so the F-35 is not a great
aircraft. It's it's extremely overpriced
and it's very hard to maintance on. So I
am not aware of these reports that the
US is is phasing out the F-35s.
Uh and yeah they they are they do want
us to buy the F-35.
So if we buy it then we'll be the
biggest fools in the world. That's
that's what I would have to say. Uh
yeah.
Uh Pesh says first of all thank you so
much sir. Thank you. So during Biden's
time, we were discussing that the US is
a declining power. Well, I have never
said that. But yeah, but what has
suddenly changed after Trump got
elected? Why is it how is it showing so
much dominance?
I So first of all, let me say I have
never ever made the claim that the US is
a declining power. I have consistently
said that the US has never been as
powerful as it as it as it is today.
It has more than 700 extr territorial
military bases all across the world. It
can strike or intervene militarily
anywhere in the world at roughly 60
minutes notice. It controls so many
countries. It controls NATO, the NATO
nations. It controls the EU nations. It
controls Japan. It occupies Japan
physically. It occupies South Korea
physically. It has never been as
powerful as it is today. I don't know
who has been discussing that Biden
during Biden's time that USA was
declining. There is societal decline in
the US. There is moral decline in the
US. But from a hard power perspective,
the US has never been more powerful. And
now that Trump is president, he's
throwing his tantrums. He's throwing his
weight around. And the US has the
capability to throw its weight around.
So it's visible now. Right? So during
Biden's time, uh that was not the case.
Biden was a pretty laid-back president
and the US did not did they start a war?
The Ukraine war started during the time
of course but that was a different
story. The US directly did not start it
but beyond that there was no other
tantrum that the Americans threw but
during Trump's time we have tantrums
every every 15 minutes. So it is
powerful. It is not declining in power.
It is actually growing in power. The
society in the US is declining. There is
societal decline, societal decay, moral
decay, all of that. But as a hard power,
it's never been stronger. All right? So
think of it, think of it that way. You
to categor you to compartmentalize these
two two things separately. Societal
decay, moral decay is different from
your hard power status. Your hard power
is is superb right now for the US.
Society in the US is decaying,
declining,
moral decay, decay in value, values and
ethics and whatnot. educational system
is is becoming crap and so on. But as a
hard power, it's still powerful, but
we're not sure how long that lasts. So,
we'll see.
Okay, Rahul. Well, thank you so much. I
really appreciate the
this comment. Thank you so much.
Appreciate it.
Anonymous scientist says, "Is bricks
falling apart?" It's not quite falling
apart, but it's not very cohesive also.
Um, that's a bricks bank and whatnot,
but beyond that, it's a coalition of
very unlikely partners. India, Russia
makes sense for them to collaborate
together because they are natural
adversary, natural partners. Okay. But
India and China are are adversaries
right now and China and Russia are
natural adversaries.
So the the the core of bricks is racial
India China and only Russia and India
can work together as natural partners.
Russia and China are actually long-term
adversaries and India and China have
issues. So bricks is not a very
long-term viable thing. It's something
that will continue for a while but M but
it's not entirely falling apart at the
point at this point in time. Not falling
apart but but not very impactful is what
I would say. Uh Rajit Raj says there's a
declassified CIA document on AEL
projection. I think it proves it. I
don't remember accurately. Is that a
legit source of inco info? I'm aware of
these uh de supposedly declassified CIA
documents. Okay. Uh some speak about
project stargate or something about a
projection. Some speak about remote
viewing uh whatever. Okay. Just because
the CIA has put out some documents
doesn't mean it proves anything. It is
just a claim.
How can we say that something is proved?
If the CIA puts out a document making a
claim and you can replicate that
independently of the CIA using the
information they have given then it is
proven. See this is called critical
thinking.
How do you know whether something is
proven or not? The CIA has made a claim.
How have they made the claim? by putting
out some research documents in the
public domain in which they claim that
so and so CIA subjects in so and so year
did so and so thing and this so so and
so thing it's a claim they have made so
does it mean it's proven
how do you know if it's proven it is
proven if using that information in the
document you can replicate that
experiment successfully otherwise it is
just a claim blah blah blah
So in my opinion, this is an empty
claim. It is not a legit source of info.
I am a super skeptical person. I don't
believe things that easily
and I don't believe the CIA thing.
Uh, Eris Montikor says, "Is it true that
Israel remodified the source code of the
F-35 salt to them and improved its
operational efficiency to such a degree
that the Americans have decided never to
share the source codes of the F-35s? I
don't know. This is deeply classified
information.
This sort of information will not be
available to somebody like me. Okay? Not
to me. I'm a dangerous person. I should
not know such information. So this sort
of information I am the last person who
will receive it. It's possible that they
may have done it. Possibility exists.
But do we have proof? We don't have
proof. At least I don't have proof and
I've seen no proof. But now understand
this. The US is Israel's number one
ally. Unconditional support is given to
Israel. No matter what Israel wants or
needs, the Americans provide it. Right?
So if the Israelis said to America, we
have these F-35s, we need the source
code. I am pretty sure the Americans
would have given them all the source
code. I'm pretty sure they would have
given it. They will never say no to
Israel. They will deprive Australia of
source codes, but never Israel.
So it is, I think, likely I think it's
highly likely maybe maybe 90% plus
likelihood probability that Israel was
given the source code. Okay, I'm just
making a guess, an educated guess. And
if Israel was given the source code,
then it is a guarantee that they would
have modified it and improved upon it
because they have got very good
programmers. No question. Right. Now,
does it mean that this would have
induced the Americans to decide that we
will never share the source code of
F-35s? No.
No.
The Americans would have already decided
even before they gave Israel anything
that we will never give the source code
to anybody else.
Okay. So, yeah, that's the deal. That's
how I see it. That's how I see it. Um,
Rishi says, "What are your thoughts on
the current tax system in in India?
Taxes are high for everything, even a
regular car. Will the government try to
reduce taxes?" I think it'll be very
good if the government reduces taxes. I
think the tax system is extraordinarily
over complicated for no reason
whatsoever. I do understand that the
government needs to charge taxes. That's
how we run the country. No question
about it.
But do you need to have such a
complicated and cumbersome taxation
system? Do you need that?
So let's say you are a salaried person.
That's that itself is such such a
tragedy. So heartbreaking. You're a
salaried person. So let's say you're a
salaried person. Let's say you earn 1 cr
a year. Okay? Completely hypothetical
number. We are just putting it out
there. Let's say you earn 1 cr a year or
let's say let's say you earn 10 lakhs a
month. Okay,
which is 1.2 crores a year. Um, so what
happens is that every
the cycle at end of April or whatever it
happens, you have to pay your income tax
and of course your company is going to
deduct the income tax and whatever you
know TDS or whatever they call it before
you even get the salary. So you get the
salary with the tax deducted already
from it. So you would don't get the 10
lakhs per month. You get whatever amount
is given to you after cutting off the
tax. So the amount that you get is
already taxed. Now you take that taxed
money. They already pay the taxes. Now
you go to a supermarket, you want to buy
a Coke, you're going to pay some GST on
that. So you paid tax once, you pay tax
on that tax. Then let's say you buy a
car, you have to pay tax for that car.
Then then you have to pay road tax. So
you taxed multiple multiple multiple
multiple times. It is horrible. It's
it's terrible.
Why can't you just levy one tax? I think
the taxation system exists just to keep
give people employment.
If you you can replace this horrific
taxation system by a very with a very
simple tax system. Everybody will be
taxed a simple flat rate whatever maybe
20% maybe 25 whatever it is everybody
should be taxed the same tax rate.
decide in which way it will be done and
just make it simple. So there is no need
for this over complicated system. It can
be simplified if you want to and it
should be but I think that the taxation
system exists to provide employment to
cr of people. That's my hunch and if you
remove employment then the government
will not get votes. So that's the system
in India.
Anyhow, Shivam Kulkarnney, well, thank
you so much for becoming member. Thank
you. I appreciate that. Uh, Vishal Nata,
thank you very much. Thank you.
Um, Austin Joseph says, "Well, first of
all, thank you for your kind words, sir.
Uh, my question is that India has been
bending
B."
Okay. India. Okay. India has been India
has been bending over to the US or Kata.
India canceled many deals with Russia
who has been our long-term partner for
70 years. Your views
um
you raise good points here. See the
situation is complex.
Has Russia been a fair all-weather
friend for India? First let's let's
address the Russia question.
So Russia during the cold war the 20th
century was India's number one partner
very reliable partner um and it came
came to a rescue at times like the 71
situation where the Americans sent two
aircraft carrier strike groups to India
to the Bay of Bengal and so on the
Russians sent nuclear submarines and so
on. So Russia was a very reliable
partner
during the cold war. After the cold war
ended and the USSR became Russia, Yelson
came to power. Russia's attitude towards
India changed significantly and they
kind of were very dismissive towards
India for quite some time. So our
politicians then needed needed a new big
daddy. So they started looking at the US
and slowly the US started infiltrating
India. Okay. At the top levels and so on
so forth. allegedly allegedly allegedly
allegedly
then Mr. Putin comes to power and once
again relations start becoming better
between India and Russia. Now in the 20
2010s around 2015 to 2021 or something
Russia started courting Pakistan
Russia sold military helicopters to
Pakistan under Mr. Putin. Russia and
Pakistan started doing this yearly
military exercises together called the
Durjba exercises. Durba is the word in
Russian which means friendship. Russia
Pakistan friendship. They started doing
Dujba exercises every year. One year in
Pakistan, the other year in Russia, then
again in Pakistan, then then again next
year in Russia. This went on until 2021.
Then in 2022 there was no Durushba
exercise. Why is that?
Because there was the special military
operation in which Russia needed India's
help and support.
So you see even Russia has played these
games. Even they
have sold military equipment to
Pakistan. They also
were wooing Pakistan and doing dujba
friendship exercises with Pakistan. So
because of that attitude of Russia's
India also
uh decided to to open up its dealings
with other countries uh signed the Katsa
with the US and other things as well
right perhaps and and when it comes to
the FGFA the fifth generation fighter
aircraft the PAC FA50 or whatever it was
the Russians were continuously delaying
the project they were not sharing
sufficient technology with India and all
they were they had a very non-cor
cooperative attitude which is after
spending so much money India had to pull
out of the project even when it comes to
the aircraft carriers the aircraft
carrier costs were blown out of
proportion India had to pay way much
more than what we had initially agreed
to and so on so Russia has been a
difficult partner at multiple times
right so it makes sense for India to
have other options and that's why India
had India was forced by Russian actions
to cancel deals with Russia because even
after spending so much money we were not
getting what we were paying for. So then
it makes sense to not not to sink in
more money. It was not our fault. It was
Russia's fault this happened. The the
fighter plane thing and so on so forth.
Uh now obviously if you sign the CAT
side it kind of compromises you. So
that's not a good thing but we did that
and uh we then bought various American
equipment like the Poseidon fighter
plane the the the the sea guardian and
land guardian whatever drones air
guardian drones and and many many more
things. the the Chinuk helicopters, the
Apache helicopters which are not
functioning very well, the the F uh the
the jet engine deal for the Thousas
fighter plane which is again stuck
because of the Americans and so on. So
even the American things have not worked
out very well for us. Okay, it actually
compromises us. But overall I would say
that our our our more reliable partner
is Russia, not the US. The US is a very
very dangerous customer and not a
reliable partner at all. Um so as we
grow as we rise it makes sense for
Russia to once again um you know deal
with us in a in a in a better way. So
that's where we are. See geopolitics is
like that. Even if you have the best of
relations if you become weak then your
your partners will not uh respect you
too much. So you have to grow stronger.
Uh Vidi says which country has the best
education system in the world and why
they they say it's Finland. So in
Finland, you don't have to pass exams
until a certain age and all. Uh as long
as you're a kid, you don't have any
exams. You don't have any curriculum.
You can do whatever you want. You can
play outside, outdoors. You can pursue
whatever subjects catch your fancy. But
eventually it works out fine. And the
kids turned out to be very well balanced
and very well uh educated. So maybe
Finland has the best education system in
the world possibly. I haven't really
studied all the education systems, but I
think Finland is said to be the best
one.
Aries manticor says the CIA has
terrorized the US citizens more than
more than more than any terrorist drugs
psychological operations murders etc.
Could it have contributed to the decay
of US society?
Um well that could be one contributing
factor could certainly be one of the
contributing factors. The other factors
could have been the infiltration of the
leftists into all the big US
institutions especially the education
institution and the way they hijacked
the feminist movement and the civil
rights movement and other other
movements. Um yeah so all of these
things put together have contributed to
the ongoing decline and decay moral
decay of US society. Drugs everybody
drug does drugs in the US. It's a right
of passage. You can't think of a single
person in the US who I mean if you meet
an American person the chances are
higher that the person has done drugs
and not done drugs at some point in
their life. Everybody does drugs.
Everybody is on anti-depressants or or
like a dozen pills a day. I mean the
food is terrible. If you if you spend a
month in the US, you're going to gain 5
kilos at least. Yeah. You're going to
become unhealthy. It's it's it's a
disaster as a society. So it's not just
the CIA. CIA could also be a significant
causative factor for sure, but it's a
multiplicity of causes all all brought
together. The corruption in the the
society in the system how big pharma has
destroyed the health of the the US
population for profits and and the
politicians have allowed this to happen
because they are in the pockets of big
pharma. This is corruption at the at
every level of US society. You know they
talk about India being a corrupt
society. not society but a system the
governance system in India being
allegedly super corrupt it's nothing
compared to the US nothing
uh Ragav says why are okay Ragav says
there are many Iranian people migrants
in Hyderabad who even voted for Iranian
elections around the year 2000 and who
have dual citizenship Iran and India why
are they enjoying the status well what
I'm not aware of this there are Iranian
people
migrants in Hyderabad who voted for
Iranian elections in the year 20,000 in
the future but I'm I'm sure you mean
uh who have dual citizenship Iran and
India well in India dual citizenship is
not legal you are not allowed to have
dual citizenship if you have a
non-Indian passport you automatically
become an relinquish your Indian
citizenship
unless you don't disclose the fact you
have your foreign passport and you keep
two passports for some people I suppose
may be doing such
one one hears allegedly that such things
happen but I don't know uh
so if there are people who have dual
citizenship they're not supposed to have
this dual citizen citizenship uh why are
they enjoying the status well first of
all I don't know that this is the case
but if it is true then the government
should look look into it and uh they
should look into the legality of the of
the matter that what citizenship do
these people actually have according to
Indian law is it is it Iranian or is it
Indian if they have actually both then
they should be made to ask to make a
choice decide you can only have one
according to our laws you can only have
Indian citizenship if you don't have a
foreign citizenship so decide do you
want to remain Indian citizen then you
give up your Iranian passports and so on
so that needs to be done um there are so
many such problems in India so many
people who are enjoying Indian
hospitality some of them are civilized
most of them are not civilized uh some
of them are really problematic I would
say Iranians overall are not that
problematic as a as as a population is a
people. Uh but when it comes to
Pakistanis
or or or or
Rohingyas or cookies or Bangladeshes, we
don't want those in India.
Big problem. They have no allegiance to
India and so on. So this needs to be
dealt with. This illegal immigration
problem needs to be seriously dealt
with. It's a huge huge massive national
security issue for us.
Okay. The rational reporter says, "I
designed an AI that generates optimized
readings for retaining walls in 5sec. My
company organized demonstrations,
verified and appreciated it, provided a
small salary increment, and abandoned
the project."
Well, that's sad, and I'm sorry to hear
that, my friend.
Yeah.
So, you clearly have some talent.
some skills in um designing and and
creating AI systems. So what I would
recommend to you is
spend some time outside of work at home
or wherever and build some AI systems
that solve real world problems and then
monetize those
because if you provide some value to
society, society will be willing to pay
you money for it.
So identify some some existing problems
in society that something that people
want but don't have and would be willing
to pay for and and create an app or
something create multiple apps put them
on whatever Android
um iOS whatever
monetize it and if it works out if it
generates sufficient money you could say
bye-bye to your company.
So that's one one one one thing you
could do but otherwise if you're in a
company then the then the leadership
will decide what happens you decide you
you create something wonderful but
they'll say it's not worth it or we
don't see any value in it then then they
can kill the project and that's
something that makes you feel completely
helpless right and yeah I mean if you I
remember many years ago I I partially
read the autobiography of Dr. APJ Abdul
Kalam
I I read some of it it's called wings on
fire or something in which he wrote
about the fact that he had designed a
warcraft
he had built a prototype hovercraft
which worked very well but his superiors
killed the project
and there was nothing he could do about
it but he went on in life and did much
greater things so you can learn
something from the great Dr.
Don't give up. Don't feel sad. I know
it's sad. I know it's um despiriting but
but you have the talent. You have the
skills. Use it to create something good
and valuable. All right sir. All the
best. Vishal Nasa says okay Vishal
Natha. Well thank you so much sir. Thank
you. Thank you. You could have asked a
question but all right thank you so
much. Um Deepak Tvata says why is Iran
important for India? Because it's an
independent country reasonably sovereign
country that exists in the West Asia
region. Uh we don't have any major
issues with Iran. We are not enemies by
any by any uh yard stick. Iran um the US
is not a friendly nation to India. It is
propping up the terrorist nation
Pakistan. It's providing it with nukes
and so on. It's been it has funded and
financed Pakistani terrorism against
India for decades. The US and the the
Iranians stand up against the US. So
they kind of create a certain balance of
power in the region which if if it falls
it will be disaster for India. If Iran
falls and becomes a US vasal then the
entire west Asia region will be
dominated by the US and then even Iran
will be an empty nation just like
Pakistan. That's why it it's important
it doesn't happen and Iran has provided
us with access to the Chabahar port
through which we can access Central Asia
that also goes away.
So overall Yeah.
That's why it's important for India. Uh
Aries Manticor says, "I saw a report
that the Indian government has placed a
caveat on the Sukoy 57E deal, Indian
radars instead of Russian radars.
Certain components to be sourced only
from India. What do you think of this
move? How will Russia react? I think
it's a fantastic move. I think we have
certain technological capabilities that
exceed those of Russia. I think uh the
radars we are developing the gallium
arsenide or whatever radar it is u
whatever it is uh I think it'll be
superior to what the 57 will come with.
So I think it is perfectly fair for us
to place some caveats some conditions
that yes we'll be happy to u purchase
the sukoy 57e and manufacture it in
India in large numbers but we will need
these modifications and we will do the
modifications ourselves. So we will
install our radars and some components
will be sourced from India. Some weapon
systems will be Indian weapon systems
instead of Russian weapon systems. For
example, the Astra BB RAM. That's a
frighteningly dangerous missile. It it's
a guaranteed aircraft killer, right? We
have that missile. Why would we use a
Russian missile? So yeah, so some
components can be some Russian
components should be replaced with
Indian components. And what do I think
of this move? I think it's an excellent
move. How will Russia react? I think
Russia will react positively to it and
Russia may even possibly want to source
some of those technologies from us. If
it happens, we should be uh eminentable
to that happening. So I think I think
Russia will react posit positively to
this.
Um
Bobby Bobby good to see Bobby again
longtime viewer. Good to see you sir. I
hope you're doing well. So Bobby says,
uh, what was China's actual
contributions?
What, what's the question, Bobby? What
was China? Okay, I think you're saying
China. What was China's actual
contributions to what
to Indian culture? Are you asking or are
you talking about uh to the field of
sports literature or Persian literature
or quantum field? What what what's the
question, sir?
What was China's actual contributions to
what? Without that I will not be able to
answer your question. Sorry, very sorry
but but good to see you and I I hope
you're doing well sir.
Uh Dirj Kamat says ideas for tools or
products you would use I would want to
build. What would I want to use? Well I
have very esoteric and very strange
uses. Okay I what would I use?
I'll have to think about it. I haven't
thought about uh these days you have
tools for everything but I'm sure if you
think about it
so let's say I am into geopolitics
okay
what kind of tool would I want I would
want a system that gives me all the
information I need without having to to
go through so much noise you see if you
are into geopolitics if you if you're an
analyst if you're an observer you have
to go through so many news reports
hundreds thousands So much noise, so
much junk to find the the the the high
signal pieces. So difficult, right? So
one thing I would do, I was build I
would want somebody to build such a
system for me. That's one thing. Of
course, there are many other things I
can think of.
But yeah, uh if you ask me right now,
I'll not be able to come up with ideas,
but maybe I can do that over time.
Um okay. Okay. Um,
okay. Now, Sam the Gamer asks, "Can we
use Vietnam to counterbalance China as
in we turn Vietnam into an Indian?"
That's what Sam the Gamer is asking. Um,
yeah, Vietnam can be to some extent
hypothetically in a very completely
hypothetical scenario be used to
counterbalance China. So what you can do
is you can sell highquality weapons
systems to Vietnam. Sell them uh the
sea-based Brahos missile, sell them the
800 km range landbased Brahos missile,
sell them the Akash T system, sell them
uh various other things. Maybe sell them
submarines. Maybe sell them warships.
turn them into a military fortress that
China can't um bring down. So that is
one way you could potentially use
Vietnam to counterbalance China if
Vietnam is willing to do that. I would
not want to turn Vietnam into a vasal.
We don't do such things. Uh but yeah, if
if interests align and if if they feel
the necessity for having a robust uh um
a robust military capability to to deter
China, then it makes sense to do that
and yeah that way we can do it for sure.
Uh that is certainly a possibility for
us to uh explore.
Um
let us see let us see. Uh anonymous says
the US has offered the F-21 with
manufacturing in India. Can they pull
the put a kill switch if they
manufacture in India? 100% yes. They can
still pull it put in a kill switch.
Because see manufacturing in India means
that we will put all the components
together in India. Maybe we can make the
airframe in India. We can even melt
steel to make the airframe in India and
so much more. But some things like chips
and components will come from elsewhere.
And that's where the kill switches and
things are right and manufacturing in
India does not entirely equal
technological transfer for example the
the jet engines will come from the US
right we we will not be manufacturing
jet engines here that's a whole
different supply chain and so on so it
doesn't necessarily mean that we are
manufacturing because we are
manufacturing in India we have complete
technology transfer okay okay
um
manticor says the afterburner for Cavary
dry engine was developed by the Brahmos
engineuri agency with the gas turbine
research establishment not h your it is
going to be developed by the brahos
agency with the gas turbine research
establishment which is based in
Bangaluru it will not be done by
hindustan aeronautics limited what are
my thoughts in this move will it be
better I don't know but uh the brahos
agency uh it has historically performed
well. It has produced this frightening
missile, very accurate, very dead did
deadly missile. Um, but that doesn't
necessarily mean that they'll be able to
do the same kind of work with the cavary
engine with the after burner because
it's a whole different technology. But
I'm sure the the the personnel are
extremely high quality people, very well
skilled in all that. So I think overall
good move. I would say I'm sure there's
a reason why the government would have
chosen it to happen this way. and uh I
hope it succeeds. I hope it pro produces
the desired re results.
Uh yeah, so that's all I can say. I
don't really know what's the comparison
between the BRAOS agency u and GTRE that
combination versus Hindustan Aeronautics
Limited. Uh GTR has been working on the
cavary engine for a very very very long
time essentially since the 1980s
the gas turbine research establishment.
Uh so I think it looks like they are
getting into a collaboration with the
bramos agency. So maybe fresh ideas,
fresh blood comes in and maybe you you
get some better results out of it. Maybe
the government has seen it that way or
whatever way. So yeah, let's see how it
goes. Um
and I hope it works fine. It it it
produces
um the desired results.
Okay. Hunter canvas says who was
realistically the better ruler of India
Chandra Gupta Maria or Ashok Moria? Uh
different rulers I would say overall
Ashok was greater. Chandra Gupta
obviously was the founder of the of the
of the empire of the dynasty. He had the
help of his great mentor Shri Vishnu
Gupta Chanaka. But Ashok so generally
what happens when you have a great ruler
his descendants typically are not great.
They kind of fritter away the greatness.
But Ashoke well he took it to the whole
a whole different level. They unified
the entire subcontinent under his rule.
So I would say overall Ashok was great
greater. That's why they don't say Chad
Gupta the great. They say Ashok the
great. Of course he had some some some
flaws. He was a pretty nasty guy. He was
a pretty cruel guy. But I don't care. I
don't care because he he turned India
into this very powerful empire
superpower of its time, didn't he? Yeah.
So I I'll I'll take it. So I would say
it's Ashoke, the grandson of Chandra
Gupta who was the greatest.
Um okay, what else? What else? What
else? What else? What else? Um let's
take this one. Sid says, "Who will rule
AI and robotics world in the future
after the US and China? The US might fit
against China because of its global
talent pool. Could India or the EU be
third?
The EU? Well, they they they have some
I think the French have some AI
companies. Mistal is one. I've never
never seen it, never used it, but I hear
that there's something called Mskal,
which is reasonably good, which is a
reasonably powerful AI LLM model thing,
whatever. Yeah.
Uh so who comes third is the question.
Is it EU? Is it India? Is it Russia? Is
it somebody else? Japan is not in the
running. Russia, I'm not sure where it
is. uh India seems to be serious about
it but we haven't really seen any much
any progress thus far visible progress
it doesn't mean nothing is happening I
would say it would be a race between
India and the EU and I think India would
win overall in the next two three years
so I think by let's say 2027 it would be
the US China and India possibly and the
and the EU also will be involved but
maybe India will overtake the EU I am
pretty optimistic about
that about that
okay Uh another 10 minutes then we're
done. Okay. Ragav says they are they
actually have overseas citizenship. I
numbered them around 20,000 like Mirzas,
Shirazis etc and so on. So overseas
citizenship means do you mean it's
Indian overseas citizenship OCI
or something else? If you have OCI then
I suppose you can stay in India for
extended period periods of time and so
on. I'm not sure what the rules are.
overseas citizen of India means that you
have more rights than a person who just
gets a visa. So you I suppose you could
stay in India for an extended period of
time and so on so forth. Uh so yeah I
don't know the OCI rules and so on. Um
but yeah you if you have an OCI card you
can have a different passport. An OCI
card is not an Indian citizenship. It is
a step below Indian citizenship. It's an
overseas citizen of India. So it's not
it doesn't give you the same rights as
an Indian citizen. It's slightly it's
slightly less. So that way you can have
an Iranian passport and an OCI card.
That that can work. Yes.
Uh Deepak says origins of J what are the
origins of the Jart people and are the
Jart the oldest Indian tribe? There are
various uh theories about this. Uh
there's this article by Dr. Swashk in
which he he says that the Jats could be
connected to the uh the gate tribe. The
gate tribe who were one of the Smithian
tribes, Shaka tribes. There was this
Skithian tribe called the Masagate which
is the Mahajats
and their queen was Tomiris
and she defeated
Cyrus the great Kurush Vajarak and took
his head off. So yeah, she was great and
and and so it looks like the Masagate
tribe of the Skithians, the Shakas was
the Mahajata tribe and maybe the
Skitians when they entered India about
2.2,000 years ago uh and they settled
down in western and first northern and
then western India. Maybe some of their
descendants are what we call the Juts
today.
Uh but the Skithians themselves were not
a foreign tribe. They were descendants
of ancient Indians who migrated out of
India thousands of years ago and this
they roamed around central Asia and so
on and then eventually reentered India.
So when they reentered India and
conquered parts of India, there was
absolutely no cultural strife, nothing
at all. They simply
harmoniously assimilated into the Indian
population. They were sun worshippers.
they were polytheists and they would
have looked just like us I suppose or
maybe some little bit of foreign
influence maybe here and there but
mostly they were us
so uh it's possible that the that the
Mahajats the Masagati were a Kithian
tribe originally and they entered India
about 2.2 2 2.1,000 years ago and then
then they became Indian just like us
like everybody else. So that's one of
the theories that uh is in existence.
Yes.
Okay.
Okay. Uh Kersh says please enlighten us
on Google deep minds AI based protein
structure prediction technology. I'm not
aware of it. I have not used it. I have
not seen it. So I can't say. So protein
structure is is very complicated, right?
proteins are based on amino acids and
protein unfolding and all that is is
pretty complicated in biotechnology and
so on and uh that has pretty important
biotechnology and other medical
applications.
Um and it's pretty difficult to find new
solutions to these problems. So I think
AI can become a significant false force
multiplier in that. So maybe that that's
the deal but I haven't studied this
myself. I don't know what exactly it is.
I am not into biotechnology and all that
stuff. Uh so I don't know but yeah AI
has all these applications scientific
applications and so on so forth.
Um all right um see when I look at the
the non superchar questions I will get
all these frivolous little questions. I
am not against frivolous questions and
funny questions but look at this. I mean
look at this.
So that's why I think super chats make
sense.
I know it's a funny question and I don't
mind laughing. I don't mind laughing.
I'm not saying don't ask these
questions, but when I take super chat
questions, they're typically more
serious, right? So,
see once again, is it the same person?
Okay. So, let's maybe take a couple more
questions and then we are done. Couple
more questions. Um,
people want me to answer that question
now.
Okay.
Look, first of all, do I think Mr. Modi
and the Madame Milani make a good pair?
Look, they are pretty friendly with each
other. They like each other as as
leaders, right? They have a good uh
understanding, good rapport with each
other. But why do we have to go down
that route?
Yeah,
they clearly are very friendly with each
other. They have a great amount of
comfort and understanding with each
other, which is good to see.
And it looks like they both admire each
other's leadership and so on. So I mean
I'm happy to see that. Beyond that
there's nothing more to be said about
this. That's all I'll say.
Yeah. Sumit says Rajata people in Rajbut
community girls are comparatively more
white than others. Even males to earn
some percentage. Okay. It's possible. I
have not really uh paid attention to the
patterns but okay. You must have. So all
right. All right. All right. H
um so we are almost at the 3hour mark.
Um almost at the 3-hour mark and and
look at this and look at this more
frivolous questions. There we have it.
Uh okay. Um
okay, let's take this one. Bri says uh
will the Russians help Iran take down B2
bombers if they try to destroy the foro
underground uh nuclear facilities as
Ukraine destroy Russian bombers. The
thing about the B2 bomber is that it's a
stealth bomber and it's not easy for a
conventional radar system to pinpoint
the location of the B2. That's why it
succeeds.
So if you have a large gigantic radar,
you kind of know there's something out
there, but it's very hard to pinpoint it
and take it down. But it's it's
possible, but it's pretty hard. Uh now
the question is will Russia help Iran
take this down? Well, for that Russia
will have to put some ground forces or
some weapons on Iranian territory, which
could be a red line for some people and
so on. So I think it is pretty difficult
for this scenario to be for me to see
the scenario happening. Pretty
difficult. Looks like Iran is more or
less on its own. And if Russia gets
involved in the Iran Israel conflict,
that's going to be well a significant
escalation. Russia is already involved
in Ukraine. All kinds of issues in
Ukraine. Now, if you also start this new
war, it would be very counterproductive
and very ill advised. I don't think Mr.
Putin will go down that road. So, looks
like Iran is on its own. Sir, looks like
that.
Vina Yoshi says, "Is Pakistan suddenly
supporting Israel?" Yes, it is. Of
course, Pakistan will support whoever
the Americans ask them to support.
Pakistan is a mercenary nation. They are
a nation for sale. Their leadership is
for sale. They will do whatever the
Americans will tell them. Even support
the Yahoodis,
right? So that's what Pakistan is doing.
What about the Umah, the Islamic
community? Who cares?
Money money money money money money
money money money money money money
money money money
uh
Swaraj says why Indian government didn't
support a sort of built telescope like
Hubble James web and unique satellites
like Voyager mass o etc etc etc uh use
Google what
notebook I'm not sure about all that
look India is a developing nation
and a Hubble or a James web is a huge
luxury we don't we can't afford.
Okay. So that's in Voyager for for space
exploration. No, we will only develop
technologies that will allow us to
uh set foot on other planets and so on
and expand our footprint eventually
beyond that scientific exploration and
all that we'll do when we are a super
rich nation. Not right now. It doesn't
make sense for us to do it right now. So
that's why when you are a poorer nation,
your priorities are limited. That's why
Mcloven says, "You said the British F-35
is a is a Trojan horse. Um, can you
elaborate how it can be used to spy on
us?
Um,
so it can have sensors for example. So
let's say it's like this. F-35 comes and
lands in Thirwan and Tapuram. So India
will be tempted to use various remote
sensors in the region to try and figure
out the the capabilities and stealth
characteristics and other things of the
F-35. So we will act activate all our
sensors, right? But maybe the F-35 will
have sensors inside which will then
check out our sensors and and and and
and try and figure out what the
frequencies are being used and what are
the characteristics and and capabilities
of the Indian systems and Indian Indian
sensors. So when the operation Synindur
happened uh the Pakistanis were able to
kind of map our air defenses. Now it
will have changed but they will get some
some kind of information. What are the
characteristics of our air defense
systems? what kind of frequencies do our
radars use uh and other capabilities of
our weapon systems but and this would
have been passed on to the US because
Pakistan is a US
asset. So all of these all of this
information about Indian capabilities
during operations in Synindur would have
reached the US but the US has no idea of
our capabilities in the south
right in in places like Tvandram etc. So
maybe they want to find out what's
happening there. So maybe the F-35 is
full of sensors inside and it's sitting
there waiting for us to activate our
equipment so that it can you know make
some measurements and readings and then
eventually transmit that to the US. So
maybe that's the purpose for it being in
India and that's why I say it's a Trojan
horse.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Do we have I have got all
kinds of other questions
and if I keep taking them I will do
another three hours also. Um
let me just take maybe a couple more
questions maybe two more questions and
that should be it. Um
okay let's take this one. Goresh says
when the Indian plate collided with the
Himalayan Eurasian plate the Himalayas
were formed in the north and northeast
why don't we see a similar massive
mountain range in the northwest region
will we have the so-called Hindu Kush
mountains in the northwest the Karakuram
mountains and so on so forth we have
mountains all over the place
so it's like we have multiple mountain
ranges The Himalayas are the most
visible ones, but they're not the only
mountain range. Okay. We have other
other mountains too.
Okay.
Uh Sand says, "I have an idea to create
infinite energy and want my my opinion
using grav gravity and
gravity and
bows."
What's a bow? Buoyancy.
You mean buoyancy?
gravity to drop weight and buoyancy to
bring it up. Well, well, if you actually
do the calculations, it doesn't work.
There's no such thing as infinite
energy. It won't won't work. Lots of
people have been trying it for
centuries.
Um, they say it's not possible for me to
explain why it doesn't work without
drawing force diagrams and equations and
giving you equations. But if you work it
out from a physics perspective, from
Newtonian from Newtonian physics
perspective, it doesn't work. It's not
possible to have infinite energy. Uh
other says how is the UAE with zero
taxes generations ahead of India in
development and prosperity because of
oil.
Oil is money coming out from the ground.
That's why
that's why Karan says and this is the
final question for the day. Karan says
how do we claim skitians are are of
Indian origin if we don't prove R1A is
of Indian origin as we don't have
convincing evidences in ancient samples
and so on. So let us wait for the
samples and things to come. It will take
another 5 10 years and then we will make
the claim but I can see the patterns and
I know it.
Um how do I know the skithens are of
Indian origin?
So genetically they may be very diverse.
They may have picked up genetics from
all over the place. Mongolic, Turkish
genetics, European genetics. In Ukraine,
you hadithanian cities and those were
white skythians, Ukrainian like
skithians. So why do I claim the
skithians are of Indian origin? Well,
there are multiple reasons.
Um, one of the things is language. So we
have some attestation of the schizian
language in which it's you can see that
it's it's got clear similarities of of
any upper branch language that that
would have descended from from Sanskrit.
Then if you ask yourself what's the
origin of Indo-Uropeans in Central Asia
then it's clearly I mean if you look at
the historical known literary etc
evidence it would come from the
expulsion of various uh clans uh that
happened as a consequence of the outcome
of the battle of the 10 kings and so on.
So there are multiple patterns that that
tie together which tell me that the
skitians are an Indian were originally
an Indian origin ethnic group which went
and all across central Asia and central
Asia was then called skitya for a couple
of thousand years at least and
one of the clans was the Mahajata right
the masakate
and uh you had king queen Tomish her son
was called swar swa gapas or something
like that okay I forget the him. So if
you look at the linguistics, if you look
at the names, you had they had a king
called Paratua and so on. So there are
so many factors that tell you that there
is an Indian origin to the Skitians.
So let's not and once again like I was
saying yesterday to somebody else,
genetics is not the main thing. Culture
is the main thing. And genetics dilutes
over time. Once a group goes out of
India and spends 2,000 years out of out
of India, I promise you that genetics
will dilute. But if they can retain the
culture then that remains the original
culture and so on and so forth and so
on. So well there you have it. That's
the final question for the day. It's a
very interesting topic. The skithians I
have been studying skithians for about
20 years 20 plus years. I got interested
in this in the early 2000s because I was
researching my own origins.
I mean I never liked Indian history.
Indian history was always depressing for
me because of all the defeats and all
that stuff. But then when I got curious
about my own ancestry, my own origins, I
was like what is the ancestry of my
people of of of people who have the
surname Chava and that's when I started
looking into things and then there were
all kinds of claims that maybe the
Chavas are gujas gur or maybe they are
skitians or maybe they're Kushans or
they are Huns and that's how I started
looking into all this and then over the
years it became clear that the skitians
were of Indian origin originally
but if you want me to give you the
answer have to find so many different
sources and put them all together that
makes sense to write an article then
yeah okay so with that said this is the
end of today's uh session 3 hours 10
minutes pretty respectable long time
talking so I'll end it over here thank
you so much everybody for your questions
and I will see you very soon in next
week's live streams we'll do a lot of
those so with that said I will end it
over here please keep asking questions
keep learning
Keep thinking critically. Keep raising
your standards. And I will see you very
soon. Thank you. Bye-bye.